<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>V-Sekai - Manual</title>
<link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.2.335</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:18:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2023-03.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="changelog-2023-03" class="level1">
<h1>Changelog 2023-03</h1>
<p>This is the changelog for March 2023.</p>
<p>Godot Engine 4.0 launched on March 1st. 🎉</p>
<section id="fire" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="fire">Fire</h2>
<p>Upgrade the documentation to point to github actions.</p>
<p>Posted changes to <a href="https://github.com/godotengine/tps-demo/pull/167">https://github.com/godotengine/tps-demo/pull/167</a> to improve Github Actions export</p>
<p>Working on <a href="https://github.com/V-Sekai/blender-art-blue-tin-fox-models">https://github.com/V-Sekai/blender-art-blue-tin-fox-models</a> to get a list of prototype models.</p>
<p>Tuned the vr vingette usability feature to be more black.</p>
<p>Create an Awesome V-sekai page <a href="https://github.com/V-Sekai/awesome-v-sekai">https://github.com/V-Sekai/awesome-v-sekai</a>.</p>
<p>Migrate the manual page to https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2023-03.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2023-02.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="changelog-2023-02" class="level1">
<h1>Changelog 2023-02</h1>
<p>This is the changelog for Feburary 2023.</p>
<p>The sdk has the entire v-sekai-game project, all the builds and git .</p>
<p>The game builds can be smaller but they currently have the shared_library, the executable and the gdextension interface files. It also can launch v-sekai with openxr.</p>
<p>The builds are ranging to 10 minutes for a partially cached build on average. Engine builds take longer.</p>
<p>https://nightly.link/V-Sekai/v-sekai-game/workflows/vsk_linux_builds/main</p>
<section id="people" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="people">People</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>Someone wanted me to help out on voip so I assisted</li>
<li>A v-tuber, expiredpopsicle, is using godot-vrm! and contributed.</li>
<li>Faolan is a Godot contribtor. Fire gifted libgodot code to him and now he’s able to run his vr platform on the Meta Quest with dotnet.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="fire" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="fire">Fire</h2>
<p>I reduced iteration times on the V-Sekai cicd from 1.5 hours to 2-10 minutes.</p>
<p>I also stopped merging incomplete work. Every merge commit should stand on its own.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2023-02.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2023-01.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="changelog-2023-01" class="level1">
<h1>Changelog 2023-01</h1>
<p>This is the changelog for Janurary 2023.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2023-01.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-12.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="changelog-2022-12" class="level1">
<h1>Changelog 2022-12</h1>
<p>This is the changelog for December 2022.</p>
</section>
<section id="section" class="level1">
<h1>2022-12-05</h1>
<p>Restored AEC3 to speech for echo cancellation.</p>
</section>
<section id="section-1" class="level1">
<h1>2022-12-06</h1>
<p>Some reorganization of the the V-Sekai-game issues and the proposal repository to move bugs to V-Sekai-game and enhancements to the proposal repository. Organized the issues and put some videos for some of them. The Japanese tokyo world bug with the 30 second lag between load was funny.</p>
<p>Moved enhancements to https://github.com/V-Sekai/V-Sekai.github.io and bugs to https://github.com/V-Sekai/v-sekai-game/issues.</p>
<p>Godot Speech now includes echo cancellation using WebRTC AEC3. Thanks iFire for adding it and getting it building. (some of the builds had issues but they should be resolved) .</p>
</section>
<section id="section-2" class="level1">
<h1>2022-12-12</h1>
<p>MMMaellon updated the V-Sekai game fov to 70.</p>
<p>Lyuma — Today at 00:34</p>
<p>We had an animation meeting with people in the Godot rocketchat.</p>
<p>We went through the issues in this list: https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/16Al_PUHAUJE0S3XXtBpmA6MQIA_9sx57BXEisW1EAB0/edit#gid=0 Google Docs (Saracen / Lyuma / Fire / Tokage) A list of open issues/bugs/PRs th…</p>
<p>Pretty excited about some of these changes if they can get merged, especially the ability to extend and override AnimationNode classes, such as from a GDExtension plugin</p>
<p>We agreed to punt SkeletonModificationStack3D until 4.1. I think we will remove it from 4.0 because it is very buggy in its present state and there is not enough time to develop a good system for IK</p>
</section>
<section id="section-3" class="level1">
<h1>2022-12-15</h1>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/attachments/Screenshot_Wed_Dec_14_02-39-03_2022_VR.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">oblique clipping plane for screenspace mirrors</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>&lt;Lyuma&gt; Engine patch: https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot/tree/override_projection VR Demo branch based on Saracen’s code: https://github.com/V-Sekai/avatar_vr_demo/tree/screenspace_mirror It’s missing some of the newer changes but anyway that’s what I have.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-12.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/attachments/Screenshot_Wed_Dec_14_02-39-03_2022_VR.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="72" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-11.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="changelog-2022-11" class="level1">
<h1>Changelog 2022-11</h1>
<section id="section" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section">2022-10-05</h2>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/attachments/v-sekai-game-bug.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">v-sekai-game-bug</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/attachments/openxr_showing.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">openxr_showing</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Restored V-Sekai-Game home.</p>
<p>Worked on EWBIK as a git branch.</p>
</section>
<section id="section-1" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-1">2022-11-22</h2>
<p>Game releases are working again.</p>
</section>
<section id="lyuma" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="lyuma">2022-11-29 - Lyuma</h2>
<p>V-Sekai-game Player spawning should be working again (see their name tag at least). There’s an issue with the default sky_celebration map caused by “TestEntity” which has scene_file_path==“” and that breaks the validation logic, preventing the player from spawning, and most default maps don’t work. You need to use Mobile Dragon Shop (very dark) or Tokyo Map</p>
<p>Note that avatars are currently not working. I think I’m getting closer to identifying where the validation is causing trouble.</p>
<section id="current-state-of-v-sekai-game" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="current-state-of-v-sekai-game">Current state of V-Sekai-Game</h3>
<p>We are working on a v2 of the network architecture based on Godot’s network spawn &amp; sync system, so a lot of the code I’m editing right now is kind of legacy at this point. The new network implementation should drastically simplify the code and eliminate dozens of complex GDScript files from being needed. I still want to get this demo stable, since we will still be using the player controller and avatar loader from it</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/attachments/VSK_tokyo_map.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">VSK Tokyo Map</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>The new v2 network demo can be found at https://github.com/V-Sekai/net_demo if you’re curious. There’s no VR support planned for net_demo, but it should serve as a strong foundation going forward.</p>
<p>Avatars should show up again. There was some code mistake that triggered only when the default “mirror” was disabled and caused avatars not to instantiate, but I didn’t notice because I had turned it on in my checkout</p>
<p>I also fixed the default sky celebration map</p>
<p>Avatar bone rotations are currently broken with this setup. Seems like the head always faces a certain direction:</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/attachments/avatar_bone_rotations_are_currently_broken.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Avatar bone rotations are broken</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>


</section>
</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-11.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/attachments/v-sekai-game-bug.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="78" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-10.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="changelog-2022-10" class="level1">
<h1>Changelog 2022-10</h1>
<section id="section" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section">2022-10-01</h2>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Lyuma — 01/10/2022 I have pushed internal and external resource whitelisting at the ResrouceLoader (ResourceFormatLoaderBinary) level as a Godot engine patch.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Here’s an example of what gets printed when the above script with OS.alert() attempts to be loaded</p>
<pre><code>ERROR: user://asset_cache/81dd12d03686
0a08faba06a1b47a3a29.scn:Resource of unrecognized type in file: GDScript.
   at: load (core/io/resource_format_binary.cpp:789)
ERROR: Failed loading resource: user://asset_cache/81dd12d036860a08faba06a1b47a3a29.scn. Make sure resources have been imported by opening the project in the editor at least once.</code></pre>
<p>Note that I was forced to rebase to the latest build which includes the new build system (target=editor) most of the code I changed is in the private gitlab repo. once things stabilize and we get the build system up and running again, next step is to publish the remainder of the code on github</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>groups-4.x (and staging) were updated to latest. I attempted to update GoCD, but it’s a bit of a yolo merge, since a few pieces all had to be updated at once due to new scons target=editor argument we need to follow https://ci.v-sekai.cloud/ (log in as guest) and test the release builds</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>export builds are being created again with the new scons naming scheme. They seem to work on linux (steam deck) at least. Don’t have access to a windows machine right now</p>
</blockquote>
</section>
<section id="section-1" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-1">2022-10-06</h2>
<p>https://github.com/v-sekai/v-sekai-game is released as fully opensource.</p>
</section>
<section id="section-2" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-2">2022-10-10</h2>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>iFire (he, him) — Today at 16:33 https://github.com/V-Sekai/v-sekai-game/pull/5 added caching to reduce doing nothing builds from 2 hours to 10 minutes ish</p>
</blockquote>
<p>New contributors this week:</p>
<p><span class="citation" data-cites="Malek">@Malek</span> Awesome for being around 🐱. Contributed to designs and cheering us when we succeed. Fixed the issue with the ci/cd with the recurse submodules. Too much to list!</p>
<p><span class="citation" data-cites="gamethecupdog">@gamethecupdog</span> Helped us figured out some problems with AMD vr and V-sekai. We debugged the AMD VR launch issues and talked about fixing the vignette settings in the ui https://github.com/V-Sekai/V-Sekai.github.io/issues/378</p>
<p><span class="citation" data-cites="meowses">@meowses</span> For supporting us and watching our presentation.</p>
<p><span class="citation" data-cites="Kosyne">@Kosyne</span> For starting a topic about onboarding and our short term and long term planning.</p>
<p>@! [P1-D3] Samuel Martin <span class="citation" data-cites="Mr_Squarepeg">@Mr_Squarepeg</span> Thanks for hanging out on Sunday, we chatted about V-Sekai and played a bit of ZeroK.</p>
</section>
<section id="section-3" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-3">2020-10-15</h2>
<p>iFire (he, him) — Today at 12:34 Turned off the mesh mirror mode for avatars because of playtesting confusion.</p>
<p>Lyuma — Today at 13:04 makes sense. at some point we can add a mirror, and we need a map aligned at the right place, or a script added to maps which define where the ““mirrors”” are (there can be more than one since it’s just duplicating meshes which is cool)</p>
<p>iFire (he, him) — Today at 14:47 I added https://github.com/TokageItLab/realtime_retarget to V-Sekai’s godot engine c++ modules. Please test, <span class="citation" data-cites="トカゲ">@トカゲ</span> is looking for feedback.</p>
<p>tefusion’s gdextension addon https://github.com/tefusion/godot-subdiv is now published. https://godotengine.org/asset-library/asset/1488</p>
<p>iFire reorganized the development documentation site.</p>
<p>iFire is working on a bullet train kinetic novel https://github.com/V-Sekai-fire/INK_bullet_train world.</p>
</section>
<section id="section-4" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-4">2022-10-17</h2>
<p>Updated this website to remove the left sidebar. Added headers to decisions and the changelog.</p>
</section>
<section id="section-5" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-5">2022-10-18</h2>
<p>Godot Engine proposal meeting rejected setting float=64 as default. However official 64 bit builds have interest.</p>
</section>
<section id="section-6" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-6">2022-10-20</h2>
<p>Early morning discussion with guillefix, lyuma and fire.</p>
<p>Feature requests from the community:</p>
<ul>
<li>desktop capture</li>
<li>avatar ik</li>
<li>quest support</li>
<li>3d node graph system</li>
<li>in-game content creation</li>
<li>wasm for game scripting</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="section-7" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-7">2022-10-22</h2>
<p>Meeting between betalars, fire, lyuma, jeana and others about usability in 3d games, convention application and V-Sekai.</p>
</section>
<section id="humble-contributions-and-places-to-start" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="humble-contributions-and-places-to-start">2022-10-22 Humble contributions and places to start? ^^</h2>
<section id="premise" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="premise">Premise:&nbsp;</h3>
<ul>
<li>betalars is working on making Chaos Computer Club more accessible.</li>
<li>There has been development to create an online-platform for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chaos_Communication_Congress">Chaos Communication Congress</a> using Godot</li>
<li>It is planned to be deployed in browser, limiting it to Godot 3 for now</li>
<li>Realistically, the Congress Experience software will not be production-ready before Godot4, so starting with Godot 3 only sets us up for tech-debt and also makes cooperation with V-sekai impossible, so it was the wrong decision originally and is now being reverted.</li>
<li>Based on limited contributors and also limited time, a Prototype in Godot 3 has been scrapped and betalars reached out to the V-Sekai team for some collaboration and humble contributions</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="what-are-constraints" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="what-are-constraints">What are constraints?</h3>
<ul>
<li>Milas needs to write a masters thesis on accessibility-driven Game-Development</li>
<li>At the end of December of each year, CCC holds a big conference, this year it is going to be a decentralised bunch of small-scale events due to the pandemic</li>
<li>iFire wants to be able to present meaningful progress by march 2023</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="benefits-of-joining-online-chaos-experience-development-efforts-into-v-sekai" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="benefits-of-joining-online-chaos-experience-development-efforts-into-v-sekai">Benefits of joining online-chaos-experience development efforts into v-sekai</h3>
<ul>
<li>Pretty much all goals align …
<ul>
<li>Make it FOSS</li>
<li>Allow for player interaction and expression in an online space</li>
<li>Make 3D-level building accessible for players</li>
<li>Use Godot Engine</li>
<li>Encourage for tinkering and hacking (of the white-hat variety of course)</li>
</ul></li>
<li>… except for the fact, that online-chaos was developed for desktop browsers and not VR-Devices</li>
<li>V-Sekai is engineering-driven and lacks in UX and Design, which betalars has more knowledge in, so there is potential for synergy</li>
<li>If this collaboration is successful, it would introduce the project into a big community of developers, some of which will be happy to contribute further code</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="risks" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="risks">Risks</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Getting distracted by shiny things</strong></li>
<li>There’s currently limited interest in the chaos community at large and Betalars is still pretty junior in experience despite leading the effort of building an online-world</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="talking-points-in-the-meeting" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="talking-points-in-the-meeting">Talking Points in the Meeting</h3>
<ul>
<li>Accessibility
<ul>
<li>V-Sekai is interested in this subject, there’s an argument to be had, that XR has great potential for people with disabilities
<ul>
<li>Not having to leave their flat for social interaction is a plus</li>
<li>Being able to choose to be stealth with a bodily disability</li>
<li>More intuitive controls with tracking</li>
<li>Hand tracking can be used for signing.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Even for for visually impaired people, there are options to interact</li>
<li>Buttons
<ul>
<li>Rumble</li>
<li>Sound Feedback</li>
<li>There’s a lot of potential for work and research here, that would also benefit the godot-community by add-on development</li>
</ul></li>
<li>… and maybe by politely asking for some vital accessibility features to be pushed upstream</li>
<li>Concrete Projects are:
<ul>
<li>Subtitles</li>
<li>Introducing a Layer for alternate text / screen-reader Label3D</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Level Generation
<ul>
<li>Currently there is a lot of interest in the community on this subject, as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NeosVR">NeosVR</a>, a project with great level-building UX, has been frozen</li>
<li>Godot has a solid 3D-Level generator, that can be used by “power-users” to create 3D-Scenes</li>
<li>Expanding its feature set could benefit the Godot Engine Community at large</li>
<li>There’s the need for intuitive tools for the average user to create cool stuff in 3D
<ul>
<li>Voxel-Editors are a great first step, as they are an intuitive tool for blocking out 3D-shapes</li>
<li>Voxel Editors can be extended with</li>
<li>“Smart Voxel objects”, that can generate stuff like staircases, roofs, fences etc, that are a pain to block out within the voxel grid (and expanding the voxel grid)
<ul>
<li>3D-Generators, that based on the existing mesh can build plants for instance</li>
<li>Convenient Prop-Placement</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Level Generation References
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dd9C90G0lQo">EverQuest Next Landmark - Detail building tools</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6gHmvxduSqI">Cloud Gardens</a>, a relaxing level building game</li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yukNnKii6xg">Dreams</a></li>
<li><a href="https://crocotile3d.com/">crocotile3d.com</a></li>
<li>Minecraft</li>
</ul></li>
<li>AI-Assisted Level Generation will probably also be a thing soon</li>
<li>Designing fun player-interaction Concepts
<ul>
<li>Betalars would like to work on it, but it is hard</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Making pretty Characters
<ul>
<li>Betalars has been working on a sims-style character generator</li>
<li>Current state can be found on <a href="https://gitlab.com/divocrew/design/-/tree/chavatars">gitlab</a>
<ul>
<li>Hopefully will also benefit Godot Engine community</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Developing a Tablet-Mode for V-Sekai
<ul>
<li>There has been effort put into creating a Non-VR interaction mode</li>
<li>Currently it is pretty janky and not thought through</li>
<li>Betalars would like to improve this</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Fire’s V-Sekai priorities:
<ol type="1">
<li>a better setting to be in</li>
<li>communications between at least two people</li>
<li>better character motion via constraints, spring bones, and animations</li>
<li>better character models (betalars has a character creation system that they already developed as possible collaboration points)</li>
</ol></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="other-helpful-resources" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="other-helpful-resources">Other helpful resources:</h3>
<p><a href="https://github.com/omigroup/ux-research">github.com/omigroup/ux-research</a></p>
<p>This is the new repo for the recently formed UX Research group in OMI. Check back weekly for updates on this repo and how to get involved. - GitHub - omigroup/ux-research: This is a new working group for <a href="https://discord.gg/92fXNYXf">OMIGroup</a></p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="section-8" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-8">2022-10-25</h2>
<p>Mmmaellon’s work requires him to build an XR app using AWS Services. He wants to use that opportunity to make something that allows players to build maps collaboratively.</p>
</section>
<section id="section-9" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-9">2022-10-28</h2>
<p>ASTC work for mobile gpu textures work.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-10.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-09.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="changelog-2022-09" class="level1">
<h1>Changelog 2022-09</h1>
</section>
<section id="section" class="level1">
<h1>2022-09-05</h1>
<p>tefusion took iFire’s previous Godot Engine 3 branch and forward ported quad subdivision to an gdextension addon https://github.com/tefusion/godot-subdiv</p>
<p>We discuss with Reduz, Calinou and Lyuma about astc and limiting astc block size to 4x4, 8x8, and 12x12 block sizes. 4x4 was agreed on. Others have not yet.</p>
</section>
<section id="section-1" class="level1">
<h1>2022-09-06</h1>
<p>Restored Lillybyte’s https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/59675 Show the 3D transform gizmo in the center when otherwise offscreen work.</p>
<p>Godot Engine astc block size agreed to be 4x4 and 8x8.</p>
<p>Saracen’s Make auto-advance flag a requirement for conditional/expression evaluation with design amendments approved. https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/65312</p>
<p>https://twitter.com/KenneyNL made a V-Sekai logo for us. https://twitter.com/KenneyNL/status/1567077172866596868?s=20&amp;t=RIGyiux3A_KNX_HCLCVKvg</p>
</section>
<section id="section-2" class="level1">
<h1>2022-09-09</h1>
<p>https://github.com/Geequlim/ECMAScript/issues/131#issuecomment-1241570998 Javascript update.</p>
<p>https://github.com/fire/ewbik Collaborated with Eron and Lyuma. Worked on the design of EWBIK bone weights and bone priority. Worked on the different bone rolls vs silhouette problem in regular 3d formats versus VRM which has a indentity bone roll. (Use the original bone and then parent the change to be in ewbik bone roll.) Made the EWBIK solve less jello. Also discussion using kusudama constraints in Godot Engine core.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-09.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-08.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="changelog-2022-08" class="level1">
<h1>Changelog 2022-08</h1>
<section id="lyuma-04082022" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="lyuma-04082022">Lyuma — 04/08/2022</h2>
<p>Migrated vsk_avatar and vsk_vrm_avatar_tool to import retargeter. There is still pending work to apply the 180 degree rotation during VRM import but we’re pretty close. Newly uploaded avatars should work, but after we fix the z-forward issue we may want to upload again.</p>
</section>
<section id="ifire-he-him-26082022" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ifire-he-him-26082022">iFire (he, him) — 26/08/2022</h2>
<p>Nothing to see here, got godot 4 engine updated to the latest master.</p>
</section>
<section id="トカゲ" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="トカゲ">トカゲ</h2>
<p>Many changes to the Godot Engine 4 master retargeting and animation system were added.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-08.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-06.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="changelog-2022-06" class="level1">
<h1>Changelog 2022-06</h1>
<section id="section" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section">2022-06-24</h2>
<ul>
<li>Updated this <a href="https://v-sekai.github.io">v-sekai.github.io</a> website.</li>
</ul>
<section id="previously-on-v-sekai" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="previously-on-v-sekai">Previously on V-Sekai</h3>
<ul>
<li>Had a meeting with Lyuma, Fire, Sarcen, Silent and MMMaellon about the V-Sekai project.</li>
<li>Resolved apply style patches to 3d-audio.</li>
<li>Make V-Sekai film tests with the new Godot Engine movie maker feature.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="section-1" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-1">2022-06-05</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>Fire collaborated on godot-snappy for object snapping https://github.com/jgillich/godot-snappy</li>
<li>Try to integrate manifold again.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="section-2" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-2">2022-06-03</h2>
<p>https://gitlab.com/bramw/baserow/-/issues/998 Spent some documenting the baserow io system on Digital Ocean used to store in-progress art assets, data from research and 3d galleries.</p>
<p>Donated research on avatar generation to the MIT-licensed project at https://github.com/AtlasFoundation/OpenCharacterCreator As part of: <a href="../decisions/20220601-lightweight-quality-avatars.html">lightweight-quality-avatars</a></p>
</section>
<section id="section-3" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-3">2022-06-01</h2>
<ul>
<li><p>Lyuma uncommented some code in vsk_avatar/ik_space.gd to create IK tracking points on the server, to enable IK sync via server. TL;DR (Other peers can see other peers while connected to a server.)</p></li>
<li><p>Server sync issue removed from todo list.</p></li>
</ul>
<table class="table">
<colgroup>
<col style="width: 4%">
<col style="width: 80%">
<col style="width: 6%">
<col style="width: 8%">
</colgroup>
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>id</th>
<th>Name</th>
<th>Notes</th>
<th>Active</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>24</td>
<td>VR smooth locomotion.</td>
<td></td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>24</td>
<td>VR smooth locomotion with blackout.</td>
<td></td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>5</td>
<td>Grab an object.</td>
<td></td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>17</td>
<td>Support large uploads to the content distribution network.</td>
<td></td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>19</td>
<td>Make a video of entering the world and grabbing objects.</td>
<td></td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Trialing a fix for issue of SDFGI on VR. Was poor. Had to backout branch.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-06.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-05.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="changelog-2022-05" class="level1">
<h1>Changelog 2022-05</h1>
<section id="section" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section">2022-05-29</h2>
<p>https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot-seurat is dependent on being able to fetch 16 bit float buffers https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues/54122#issuecomment-1140414946.</p>
</section>
<section id="section-1" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-1">2022-05-29</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>Investigated technical art via breaking apart the cafe</li>
<li>Investigated <a href="https://github.com/eliemichel/DagAmendment">DagAmendment</a> for brush based refinement of csg shapes.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="section-2" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-2">2022-05-26</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>Characters now load but the pose is incorrect.</li>
<li>Maps load from a new sdk uploader.</li>
<li>The content picker is bad and ugly but usable to pick maps to host and choose avatars.</li>
<li>The server sees all clients but the clients only see the server and not each other.</li>
<li>The vr pose is incorrect but you can see the error so it hasn’t catastrophically exploded.</li>
</ol>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/https:/user-images.githubusercontent.com/32321/170520914-088ac169-12f8-44c5-b248-f2c83ca1fb3a.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">image</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
</section>
<section id="section-3" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-3">2022-05-07</h2>
<p>Completed a first stage EWBIK inverse kinematics solver to the stage one which solves but doesn’t have constraints.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-05.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/32321/170520914-088ac169-12f8-44c5-b248-f2c83ca1fb3a.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-04.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="changelog-2022-04" class="level1">
<h1>Changelog 2022-04</h1>
<p>Moved issues into the tracker.</p>
<section id="section" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section">2022-04-18</h2>
<p>Worked with manifold csg library author and was able to remove the boost dependency. https://github.com/elalish/manifold/pull/92</p>
<p>Also published a first draft on a Godot Engine master branch. See the issue for details.</p>
</section>
<section id="section-1" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-1">2022-04-05</h2>
<p>Lyuma</p>
<p>Made a lot of progress towards animation import in Unidot. Godot’s node system means that some paths become different: for example, meshes have to be reparented to skeletons; or extra levels in the hierarchy to keep track of physics bodies.</p>
<p>To this end, it is now keeping a lookup dictionary from path and component to fileID (which can be mapped to Godot node) which means animation support should be close.</p>
<p>(Also, they made a major change to the import system in 2019 which affects id numbering. Still working on it)</p>
<p>Pushed a major update to Unidot, mostly in the post_import script. It should now generate paths much more accurately to the original file, and implemented the hashing algorithm used by Unity 2019 for file ID generation, for example generating ids like 919132149155446097 for the root object.</p>
<p>This has fixed some assets exported from Unity 2019 like below, which used to fail to resolve the fileIDs for meshes! <span class="citation" data-cites="iFire">@iFire</span></p>
<p>Made some progress with terrain import in Unidot. It will import textures, normalmaps and splatmaps (creating an appropriate ShaderMaterial). My plan is to implement trees and grass using MultimeshInstance objects. With this I also now support texture assets. Texture Arrays seem to fail internally. Hard to tell if I did something wrong or something isn’t implemented on Godot’s end, but we’ll get there…</p>
<p>performance-wise, I think it’s now acceptable to just pipe all 2+ million polygons (for 1025x1025 terrain) to the GPU. I’m using tristrips so it’s mostly just 1 index per triangle. It might be better to use a more dedicated terrain system for this, so this is just a stopgap while Godot 4 is in development since the terrain systems in the asset library are not keeping up with the rapid pace of development. (if you’re interested in this subject, feel free to start a thread or reply on godot-general)</p>
<p>Terrain trees, splatmaps and materials are implemented in Unidot, converting to a single conventional terrain mesh + multimesh. I have not implemented holes yet, but if someone has an example and there is demand, I could work on it.</p>
<p>I also chose not to implement detail (grasses), because I don’t understand how detail patches are implemented, and they tend to not look that great in VR, so I’d rather work on something else.</p>
</section>
<section id="section-2" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-2">2022-04-14</h2>
<ul>
<li>Restore fix-save-as-binary so we can export projects</li>
<li>Restore elixir shared branch so we can run godot in elixir</li>
<li>Poked ludwig about diffusion net for machine learning training.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="section-3" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-3">2022-04-07</h2>
<p>FBX2GLTF and Blender importers are merged.</p>
</section>
<section id="section-4" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-4">2022-04-03</h2>
<p>iFire</p>
<ul>
<li>Made a bug report for Blender exported animation to gltf with <span class="citation" data-cites="RockyMadio">@RockyMadio</span> https://github.com/KhronosGroup/glTF-Blender-IO/issues/1613 GitHub</li>
</ul>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-04.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-03.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="changelog-2022-03" class="level1">
<h1>Changelog 2022-03</h1>
<p>Steamdeck test with V-Sekai.</p>
<p>Restored image grid in V-Sekai content picking.</p>
<p>Working with the animation team to approve the skeleton animation retargeter.</p>
<p>https://github.com/fire/geodesiac-path-on-mesh https://mindsdb.com/ https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/56902 https://github.com/KhronosGroup/glTF-Blender-IO/pull/1582.</p>
<p>Restored wasd in V-Sekai build.</p>
<p>Also the last line also reduced the warning from 700 to around 8-30</p>
<p>Last week improved openxr support but not yet locomotion.</p>
<p>Hand actions and triggers still bugged</p>
<p>Collaboration with Khronos and Lucasfilm has added gltf principled pbr to materialx</p>
<p>A static materialx baking importer has been added to a Godot Engine c++ master module</p>
<p>Abandoned the work on webview because it required too much mingw hacking of windows calls. Should have worked in msvc still https://github.com/AcademySoftwareFoundation/MaterialX/issues/874</p>
<p>Want to propose gltf specular and gltf volumetric to the godot engine rendering team</p>
<p>Worked on an idea with Krsytof https://github.com/godotengine/godot-proposals/discussions/4226 to pin inspectors.</p>
<p>Fire collaborated with Tokage and Lyuma on the UIUX of a skeletal retargeting importer</p>
<p>Started a discussion on a train station stress test. https://github.com/godotengine/godot-proposals/discussions/4233</p>
<section id="section" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section">2022-03-07</h2>
<p>OpenXR mode works!!!</p>
<p>Made a skeleton retargeting demo.</p>
</section>
<section id="section-1" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-1">2022-03-05</h2>
<section id="ellenhp" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ellenhp"><span class="citation" data-cites="ellenhp">@ellenhp</span></h3>
<p>Added a new audio effect to down-mix stereo audio to mono progressively. https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/58823</p>
</section>
<section id="fire" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="fire"><span class="citation" data-cites="fire">@fire</span></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Allow automatic lod when importing 3D scenes with Static Lightmaps https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/58548</li>
<li>productionize a clothing band / bracelet maker on 3d manifold-only meshes https://github.com/fire/geodesiac-path-on-mesh</li>
<li>play with a auto-ml thing that guesses floats, guesses classes and forecasts https://mindsdb.com/</li>
<li>working with the animation team to approve the skeleton animation retargeter. https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/56902</li>
<li>convinced the gltf blender maintainer it’s super easy to export pure 3d animations as gltf. https://github.com/KhronosGroup/glTF-Blender-IO/pull/1582</li>
</ol>


</section>
</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-03.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-02.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="changelog-2022-02" class="level1">
<h1>Changelog 2022-02</h1>
<section id="section" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section">2022-02-23</h2>
<p>iFire — Today at 07:38 Openxr is merged into Godot Engine master!</p>
<p>Lyuma — Today at 16:13</p>
<p>OVR Advanced Settings 5.4.0 is released with OpenXR playspace moving support (for devices connected via SteamVR):</p>
<p>https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/32321/155451982-8d21ca07-0178-4314-a4f2-8de56c275fa3.png</p>
</section>
<section id="section-1" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-1">2022-02-22</h2>
<p>トカゲ — 10:28 We discussed with reduz implementation of retargeting for about 8 hours</p>
<p>Lyuma — 14:02 if anyone’s interested, you can read RocketChat from a browser: https://chat.godotengine.org/channel/animation?msg=JYqzF7xviTbh5zbmm</p>
</section>
<section id="section-2" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-2">2022-02-15</h2>
<p>Fire moved multiple projects issues to https://github.com/V-Sekai/V-Sekai/issues.</p>
</section>
<section id="section-3" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-3">2022-02-12</h2>
<p>Lyuma changed RenIK to use set_bone_local_pose_override, and “hacked” skeleton’s transform to keep it centered on the hips, fixing the avatar disappearing when far from origin.</p>
</section>
<section id="section-4" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-4">2022-02-11</h2>
<p>We made a lot of progress yesterday: getting closer to OpenXR integration; fixed some issues with avatar uploading; and progress with WasGo, including the ability to create a Godot Callable which directly represents a WASM function</p>
</section>
<section id="section-5" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-5">2022-02-05</h2>
<p>Moved fire’s project notes to V-Sekai/V-sekai issues.</p>
<p>Curl has been postponed.</p>
<p>Cvtt bc6, bc7 texture compression speedup by reducing quality has been merged. Updating groups.</p>
</section>
<section id="section-6" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-6">2022-02-02</h2>
<p>Wasgo go! Restored wasgo wasm execution.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-02.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-01.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="changelog-2022-01" class="level1">
<h1>Changelog 2022-01</h1>
<p>iFire wrote with Lyuma some proposals:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>CICD as a TrueNas Scale system</li>
<li>Proposal for Github CICD actions.</li>
</ol>
<p><a href="https://github.com/BastiaanOlij/">BastiaanOlij</a> updated the OpenXR pull request so it now uses OpenXR 1.0.22 and it has that DISABLE_STD_FILESYSTEM switch in there.</p>
<section id="section" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section">2022-01-30</h2>
<p>Switch proposal website to use https://quarto.org/.</p>
<p>Updated nomnoml diagrams.</p>
</section>
<section id="section-1" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-1">2022-01-29</h2>
<p>&lt;Lyuma&gt; Merged VR support (including OpenXR and the ability to create OpenVR as a plugin) into our godot engine build.</p>
</section>
<section id="section-2" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-2">2022-01-12</h2>
<p>Material Maker was patched so that OpenEXR export don’t shift color channels in generated EXR file.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2022-01.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2021-11.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="changelog-2021-11" class="level1">
<h1>Changelog 2021-11</h1>
<section id="added" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="added">Added</h3>
<p>iFire: Added https://github.com/V-Sekai/v-sekai-proposals/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md</p>
<p>iFire: Update FBX2glTF to create packaged release tags.</p>
<p>iFire: Wild goose chased godot 3.4 webxr. the goose flew away this time.</p>
<p>iFire: Evaluating Godot 4 for the web. 2D only. Builds in a bit from itch and cicd</p>
<p>iFire: I’ll be arranging the OMI gltf2 group meeting tomorrow. It’s currently wednesday. Need figure out what people are doing and reflect that.</p>
<p>iFire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/54886 Lyuma pr for blend i/o. Pending pr proposal. Discussed with the Godot Discord community and with Reduz.</p>
<p>Lyuma: the above is in reference to the .blend, .bvh (via bleneer) and .usdz (via blender) importers for Godor 4 and 3.3+</p>
<p>iFire: Ported and split the blender assisted addons into 6 branches and 3 repos</p>
<p>theoway: Visual script updates. https://github.com/godotengine/godot-proposals/issues/3548</p>
<p>iFire: Ventured into MaterialX slack channel and asked for answers. Answers were found.</p>
<p>Lyuma: Wrote a simple .bvh importer for Godot using <span class="citation" data-cites="iFire">@iFire [He/Him]</span>’s blender importer as a base (importing using blender).</p>
<p>iFire: Onboarded a few people onto Godot 4 Groups from older versions</p>
<p>iFire: Finishing touches on blend import for Godot Engine</p>
<p>Lyuma: reworked scene export</p>
</section>
<section id="changes" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="changes">Changes</h3>
<p>iFire: Builds of fbx2gltf from github cicd are now at https://github.com/V-Sekai/FBX2glTF/releases</p>
<p>iFire: Updated the godot branch. There was some some difficult with the blend-io branch so I merged it with other branch import something</p>
<p>MMMaellon: Didn’t we use to have an IK channel? Anyway here’s some of my ideas on how I plan to revamp RenIK. I’m still hoping that EWBIK takes over RENIK’s IK solving one day, so I’m focusing on improving the walk cycle and leaving IK solving alone https://mmmaellon.notion.site/Semi-Deterministic-Walk-Cycles-dbe1dcaa307e4fb9b85dd6ee920de20c</p>
<p>iFire — 07/11/2021: Groups update to the latest Godot. 1. intersect rays api changed. 2. misc crash if precondition fails return Oops forgot to upload a few branches.</p>
<p>iFire — 08/11/2021: https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot-blender Now works on my Linux. Need some testing for Windows and Mac. Save a blend file into the godot project and it’ll be openable as scene through tricks.</p>
<p>iFire — 08/11/2021: Will be around in voice call for an 30m to 1 hour.</p>
<p>iFire — 09/11/2021: Cleared some godot engine github backlog. Wheeee</p>
<p>iFire: Mixer bug fixes have been merged https://github.com/ubisoft/mixer</p>
</section>
<section id="z" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="z">2021-11-03 21:01:24Z</h2>
<section id="added-1" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="added-1">Added</h3>
<ul>
<li>Added a change log</li>
<li>2021-11-03 21:01:24Z fire: iFire Reviewed Visual Script work prs https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/54564 https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/52218</li>
</ul>


</section>
</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2021-11.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2021-10.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="changelog-2021-10" class="level1">
<h1>Changelog 2021-10</h1>
<ul>
<li>2021-10-31 19:30:30Z fire: https://twitter.com/reduzio/status/1454867881771024391?s=20</li>
<li>2021-10-31 17:12:51Z fire: Instruction unclear. Hair stuck in gentle breeze. https://github.com/fire/TressFX-OpenGL See releases for a zip. https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/904417650510295060/2021-10-31_10-09-56.mp4</li>
<li>2021-10-31 04:08:23Z fire: Confirmed fixed my screenshots system.</li>
<li>2021-10-30 18:18:28Z fire: :danceblob:</li>
<li>2021-10-30 18:17:58Z fire: aha. yes. https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/54427</li>
<li>2021-10-30 17:59:04Z fire: Restored theme generator for groups. [reverted to editor theme] Needs time to debug.</li>
<li>2021-10-30 06:03:59Z fire: Early builds are testable</li>
<li>2021-10-30 02:20:34Z lyuma: “The VRM avatar converter has been updated at https://github.com/V-Sekai/vsk_vrm_avatar_tool and made to work with the new rotation/scale/blend_shape tracks. (generated scenes duplicate all resources, so make sure to not save as”“.tscn”“)” https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/903830713009311754/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-10-29 23:28:11Z fire: Character translation movement now works. [WASD]</li>
<li>2021-10-29 20:59:18Z fire: <protongraph> HungryProton pushed the beginning of the 4.0 port to the refactoring-4.0 branch</protongraph></li>
<li>2021-10-29 16:02:35Z fire: From Mux and related to Godot XR This is so much fun: https://youtu.be/UxZj8OOCgY4</li>
<li>2021-10-29 01:42:32Z lyuma: Here’s a video showing multiple players moving around over the network! and made it right side up by not calling set_vflip(true)! https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/903458754262089728/vsekaimultiplayer_2021-10-28.mp4 🎉 (1)</li>
<li>2021-10-29 01:26:17Z lyuma: “We might all be in error avatars, and the world might be upside down….. But. We have networking!!! (This is the first time we’ve successfully made a multiplayer connection on Godot 4 pre-alpha with Vulkan!)” https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/903454660243894352/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-10-28 09:40:10Z lyuma: https://media.discordapp.net/attachments/659137056991346708/903093451560714280/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-10-27 19:54:44Z fire: Checked material settings Lyuma. Pushed the updates.</li>
<li>2021-10-27 18:22:01Z fire: Lyuma ninja and ccache oh my. https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot/tree/ninja-ccache Based on work by dmoody256</li>
<li>2021-10-27 16:31:59Z fire: Great work humbletim https://github.com/omigroup/omi-blender-gltf/pull/1</li>
<li>2021-10-27 01:47:49Z fire: I un-archived HungryProton’s work, made a build and duplicated some trash cans. https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/902735304228737094/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-10-25 19:59:28Z fire: Rotation mode pr merged. https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/54222 Lod added 🦎 (1)</li>
<li>2021-10-25 12:23:37Z fire: Openvr update from mux</li>
<li>2021-10-25 06:39:34Z lyuma: Updated some more scripts to work with the latest engine. the groups demo is still pink with looping physics sounds, though moving the mouse appears to pan the audio, so there’s something moving somewhere</li>
<li>2021-10-24 01:37:02Z fire: “followed up on a design for duplicated blendshapes Lyuma korewaChino EIREXE https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues/54062”</li>
<li>2021-10-24 01:21:56Z fire: Tested animation compress. was a bit slow</li>
<li>2021-10-24 01:12:26Z fire: Moved key-frame reduce to 4.0 but it still has fiddly test cases. Don’t want to debug, but leaving it here. https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot/commits/keyframe-reduce Dropping it.</li>
<li>2021-10-23 15:25:29Z fire: https://twitter.com/smallseasonsbot/status/1451929853565890563?s=20</li>
<li>2021-10-23 08:08:18Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/901381505526415360/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-10-23 06:18:32Z fire: sync with samsung thorvg team need pr review about paint replacement through iteration for color replacement</li>
<li>2021-10-23 01:48:51Z fire: Got godot speech C++ module to compile. At some point in the future need to try uncompressed audio after the api changes. There’s a test project. 🗣️ (2)</li>
<li>2021-10-23 00:36:32Z fire: Extracing godot-speech into a C++ module</li>
<li>2021-10-23 00:25:44Z fire: Lyuma told me about this tool. So cleaned it a bit https://github.com/V-Sekai/V-Sekai-Blender-tools/tree/main/addons/ApplyModifierForObjectWithShapeKeys</li>
<li>2021-10-21 03:27:13Z lyuma: fire made a lot of progress debugging the frame lag and random hangs. we have mitigations for some issues, but might not be fully correct</li>
<li>2021-10-20 07:26:46Z fire: <strong>VERY POOR 1 FRAME STUTTER</strong> Got the sample working with our own build of the openvr gdextension. https://github.com/V-Sekai/v-sekai-openvr-sample/releases/tag/v0.2 Includes the godot 4 editor.</li>
<li>2021-10-18 16:33:47Z fire: https://deepmind.com/blog/announcements/mujoco</li>
<li>2021-10-18 13:59:41Z fire: mux offers to send his working openvr as an archive. He found some bugs with exporting gdextensions</li>
<li>2021-10-18 05:26:43Z fire: cyberpunkmermaid#6171 interested in clothing for avatars at omigroup</li>
<li>2021-10-17 01:02:32Z fire: https://github.com/ubisoft/mixer/pull/27</li>
<li>2021-10-17 01:01:54Z fire: Debugged why mixer crashes on 2.93 did not fix but worked around</li>
<li>2021-10-16 02:52:17Z fire: I am satisfied. Found the bug. https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/53865</li>
<li>2021-10-16 00:33:27Z fire: What can we do to speed up our processes? https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/speed-matters/</li>
<li>2021-10-16 00:22:51Z lyuma: Updated Unidot Importer to work with latest master. Godot has gotten quite a lot faster it feels like</li>
<li>2021-10-15 23:05:50Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/53821#issuecomment-944785300</li>
<li>2021-10-15 22:29:11Z fire: “https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot-4-animation-vrm-sample</li>
</ul>
<p>Currently the root motion is on the hips and not on the root bone so it’s a bit funny”</p>
<ul>
<li>2021-10-15 22:22:01Z lyuma: “Rumors of a Godot 4 alpha are beginning to emerge. From Akien: &gt; New 4.0 build which is not alpha yet hohoho https://downloads.tuxfamily.org/godotengine/testing/4.0/4.0-dev.20211015/</li>
</ul>
<p>Some hints that it could be ““a few days more to mature”” beyond ““this week”” so there’s a chance of next week even!”</p>
<ul>
<li>2021-10-15 14:10:43Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/53833 📽️ (1),🎞️ (1),🧹 (1)</li>
<li>2021-10-15 01:33:14Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues/53823 Saracen PREVIEWS ARE FIXED 🔥 👍 (2)</li>
<li>2021-10-14 15:08:32Z fire: Watching https://vive.com event.</li>
<li>2021-10-14 14:12:59Z fire: Typed a plan for EWBIK work https://github.com/godot-extended-libraries/ewbik/issues/6</li>
<li>2021-10-13 11:49:07Z fire: Worked on トカゲ VRM-like rotational rest pose baking https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot/tree/bake-rests</li>
<li>2021-10-13 11:03:55Z fire: Skeleton split transform 3d merged from reduz</li>
<li>2021-10-13 09:20:44Z fire: Updated Lyuma https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot/tree/groups-4.x-remove-separate-gltf-bake</li>
<li>2021-10-13 04:57:28Z fire: Updated https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot/tree/rot-interpolate</li>
<li>2021-10-12 10:54:44Z fire: Akien mentioned libacktrace</li>
<li>2021-10-11 18:46:53Z lyuma: “Spent all day researching nonunknown’s negative scale issue: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/53642#issuecomment-940357171 I think I have a pretty good understanding of why it breaks in Godot (except cull_back meshes) and what solutions are possible/feasible.”</li>
<li>2021-10-11 15:57:30Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/897150929911021619/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-10-11 15:03:44Z fire: Updated blockmesh models https://github.com/V-Sekai/art-blue-tin-fox-models/releases/tag/latest. Edited: Incorrect export. Exported again.</li>
<li>2021-10-11 13:24:24Z fire: Restored compilation of lasso.</li>
<li>2021-10-11 12:56:20Z fire: Today’s Godot Engine build tag https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot/releases/tag/groups-4.x.2021-10-11T123723Z</li>
<li>2021-10-10 22:50:47Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/896892548528889896/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-10-10 22:48:25Z fire: Trialing windows 11 and WSL for CUDA on windows. It works</li>
<li>2021-10-10 22:48:09Z fire: Silent Sure, at least the permission to use them and if it’s not too much effort.</li>
<li>2021-10-10 10:18:21Z Silent#0264 Do you want the source text?</li>
<li>2021-10-09 23:24:05Z fire: Lyuma EIREXE https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/lookingglass/looking-glass-portrait with https://github.com/CaptainProton42/GodotHoloPlay https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/896538541402783774/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-10-09 18:21:42Z fire: Silent Trying to create your list of CC0, CC-BY avatars https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/896462441221877790/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-10-09 18:20:55Z fire: Creating a list of VRM checking conditions. https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/896462244378996756/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-10-08 17:31:13Z fire: https://twitter.com/smallseasonsbot/status/1446491101490081802?s=20</li>
<li>2021-10-08 17:01:37Z fire: Does not support blend shapes in bake, but does in player.</li>
<li>2021-10-08 17:00:47Z fire: See <code>addons/miku_motion_bake/readme.md</code> for instructions</li>
<li>2021-10-08 17:00:26Z fire: Been working on baking from VMD to VRM. Promising. https://github.com/V-Sekai/MikuMotionVSekai</li>
<li>2021-10-07 07:42:12Z fire: “youwin — Yesterday at 21:03 started work on an obs &lt;-&gt; godot integration using obs-websocket. Might be useful for tutorial makers or recording short demo clips of your game without requiring too much editing https://github.com/you-win/obs-websocket-gd” 👀 (3),👍 (1)</li>
<li>2021-10-06 20:26:41Z fire: Notes from GDC - Genshin Impact: Building a Scalable AI System humbletim https://hackmd.io/SPqekctOQYS5vQ7w7glJ5A</li>
<li>2021-10-06 20:10:50Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot-proposals/issues/3394 reduz wrote a proposal for ellenhp</li>
<li>2021-10-06 20:07:47Z fire: Decreasing GLB (probably VRM) sizes https://forum.playcanvas.com/t/tricks-to-decrease-morph-target-sizes/18628/9?u=chris</li>
<li>2021-10-06 19:51:03Z fire: Trialing https://v-sekai.budibase.app Lyuma</li>
<li>2021-10-06 19:34:12Z fire: Discussed with Ob5vr about blend shape baking. TODO: Get some GDC courses from The Last of Us Part 2 on SSD techniques.</li>
<li>2021-10-06 19:21:20Z トカゲ: “Marged Skeleton Gizmo 🎉 https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/45699” gdhearteyes (1),PartyParrot (2),mikuleek (1),SkellyDance (1)</li>
<li>2021-10-06 19:17:15Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/53298</li>
<li>2021-10-06 19:05:46Z fire: Also to bake blend shapes.</li>
<li>2021-10-06 19:05:37Z fire: The goal is to remove the dem bones repo is remove FBX and ABC depenencies</li>
<li>2021-10-06 19:04:50Z fire: https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot-dem-bones/tree/godot working on it for a few hours</li>
<li>2021-10-06 19:01:30Z fire: Still working on a summary of UIUX proposals. https://hackmd.io/26BUnwWOSYuMFIvvpoLa5Q</li>
<li>2021-10-06 13:18:17Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/53473 Lyuma トカゲ 🆗 (1)</li>
<li>2021-10-05 07:01:01Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/894841592505069599/unknown.png pog (2),😍 (2)</li>
<li>2021-10-05 06:50:22Z lyuma: we can chat more about this in #server-backend</li>
<li>2021-10-05 06:44:14Z fire: https://twitter.com/JenMsft/status/1445065715698962442?s=20</li>
<li>2021-10-05 04:55:21Z fire: Donmcurdy chat about materialx in omigroup’s gltf extensions discord for a few hours ❤️ (2),👏 (2)</li>
<li>2021-10-04 17:03:45Z fire: GLTF2 Document merged.</li>
<li>2021-10-04 08:21:47Z lyuma: トカゲ let’s move this to #animation … but basically there are three different proposals from Reduz.</li>
<li>2021-10-04 08:21:42Z トカゲ: So it should not support A pose -&gt; T pose</li>
<li>2021-10-04 08:21:02Z トカゲ: If I understand correctly from my discussion with reduz, this implementation is pretty similar to the global transform in MMD</li>
<li>2021-10-04 08:18:08Z lyuma: I believe this proposal is sort of a generalization of the retargeting system you might find in Unity, without going into specifics on the implementation of the retargeting: what Reduz calls a “Retargeter” is what you would call an “Avatar” in Unity.</li>
<li>2021-10-04 08:15:31Z lyuma: “Reduz made a new proposal related to Animations: https://github.com/godotengine/godot-proposals/issues/3379”</li>
<li>2021-10-04 05:35:48Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/50964 Updated libcurl. Ready for merging.</li>
<li>2021-10-04 01:59:46Z fire: Branch created https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot/tree/remove-skeleton-ik-3d</li>
<li>2021-10-03 19:51:15Z fire: https://www.campaign.viveport.com/step-into-catart</li>
<li>2021-10-03 19:49:11Z fire: https://autodesk-forks.github.io/MaterialX/ materialx web viewer</li>
<li>2021-10-03 19:48:47Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/894310029715464262/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-10-03 05:35:20Z lyuma: This isn’t really a discussion channel so I’ll continue in #server-backend</li>
<li>2021-10-03 04:37:57Z fire: v-sekai.org’s ssl cert will expire in 2 days</li>
<li>2021-10-02 19:26:59Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/53337 merged</li>
<li>2021-10-02 16:51:51Z fire: Need to a tech limits design. The Last of Us Part II Abby has a total joint count of 1075 Animated - 520 (includes face) and 555 procedural.</li>
<li>2021-10-02 16:34:45Z fire: “Everything is back to working. Yesterday everything broke ref: meshes disappeared and crash with skeleton because minimum verts. Fixes from Lyuma. Also tested occulusion culling”</li>
<li>2021-10-02 14:35:34Z fire: Lyuma The platform creator of Tokyo Game Show 2021 liked my post. https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/893868818038915132/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-10-02 12:52:57Z Saracen: Cool, I’ll read through it later today</li>
<li>2021-10-02 12:48:43Z lyuma: “Saracen fire New proposal by reduz for animation import without bone rest pose: https://github.com/godotengine/godot-proposals/issues/3377”</li>
<li>2021-10-02 02:32:49Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot-proposals/issues/3375</li>
<li>2021-10-01 07:54:55Z Saracen: Neat!</li>
</ul>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2021-10.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2021-09.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="changelog-2021-09" class="level1">
<h1>Changelog 2021-09</h1>
<ul>
<li>2021-09-30 18:33:19Z fire: Saracen https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/52210 https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/893203877367779408/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-09-30 01:28:33Z fire: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dp42lQYVzwo&amp;t=47s</li>
<li>2021-09-29 22:12:20Z fire: Holoplay initial commit https://github.com/CaptainProton42/GodotHoloPlayExtension</li>
<li>2021-09-29 22:08:01Z fire: “Fales 12:31 PM Okay peeps, I got the WebRTC plugin for 4.0 to build on all platforms (and most architectures): https://github.com/Faless/webrtc-native/actions/runs/1288153747 .” 👍 (1)</li>
<li>2021-09-29 21:39:33Z fire: Closed 6 bugs related to 53114</li>
<li>2021-09-29 21:03:56Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/53114 Merged</li>
<li>2021-09-29 20:23:20Z lyuma: “Posted the glTF export bugfix for review. Fixes blend shapes, skeletons and nested bone attachment hierarchies: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/53114”</li>
<li>2021-09-29 10:10:12Z lyuma: Successfully exported a glTF model with multiple surfaces and blend shapes: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/892714872012406794/unknown.png kickass (2)</li>
<li>2021-09-28 22:34:20Z fire: <player two=""> has entered the discussion</player></li>
<li>2021-09-28 22:33:40Z fire: Spent some time at OMIGROUP discussing OMI-WASM-ECS</li>
<li>2021-09-28 16:33:48Z fire: https://twitter.com/mux213/status/1442820373322420224?s=20 😎 (2)</li>
<li>2021-09-28 16:25:34Z fire: Updated https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot/tree/export_skin_fixes to master</li>
<li>2021-09-27 21:24:18Z fire: &gt; From reduz all would you be up for an animation meeting tomorrow?</li>
<li>2021-09-27 19:30:01Z fire: point to child and point to global as a skeleton modifier. just dreamed this. Per frame 😱</li>
<li>2021-09-27 17:03:16Z fire: https://github.com/GodotVR/godot_xr_reference</li>
<li>2021-09-27 15:31:37Z lyuma: “Nice blog post by Mux about GDExtension! A good read: https://godotengine.org/article/introducing-gd-extensions Maybe we can try making one of these for VRM springbone” 👍 (2)</li>
<li>2021-09-27 14:32:29Z fire: Wrote down a bake miku miku motion workflow. With a rebased 3.x (not 3.3) we can export the baked scene with a manual step to delete the face / blendshapes. Remember to copy both the reset and the transferred anim. Then in 4.0 import and put it on the original vrm. Enable RESET bake.</li>
<li>2021-09-27 14:26:53Z fire: Reviewed godot-tests pr and had some comments. Added a comment to fix export of skeletons and skins. Tested the export more. Noted a weird issue where if the blend was animated it would cause the blend shape to be exported wrong. Like <code>a</code> shape mouth blend set to 1.0 and looking in blender</li>
<li>2021-09-27 14:25:36Z fire: Approved gltf2 making light activate again. Discussed IK with Eron and on VRM rests.</li>
<li>2021-09-27 12:51:50Z fire: I exported the scene from your pr. Testing it with joy set to 1. https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/892030776210780210/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-09-27 07:18:36Z fire: godot-tests? ✅ (1)</li>
<li>2021-09-27 07:18:31Z fire: Lyuma want to add cursed hat to the models repo?</li>
<li>2021-09-27 07:01:50Z lyuma: Pushed pull request https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/53114 to address gltf skin and skeleton objects being generated at the wrong time during the export process. Still in draft state because it needs more testing.</li>
<li>2021-09-26 11:28:12Z Saracen: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/53086 🐱 (2)</li>
<li>2021-09-24 18:21:54Z fire: Ellenhp discussion about HRTF audio in the audio channel in chat.godotengine.org.</li>
<li>2021-09-24 14:59:37Z fire: Good news everyone. https://twitter.com/yunayuna64/status/1441288908659048453</li>
<li>2021-09-23 22:43:33Z lyuma: “Just resolved yet another server downtime. It was down overnight because I was unavailable to investigate due to an appointment. Cause for failure: Fedora (without NetworkManager?) defaults to non-daemonized dhclient and allowed the dhcp lease to expire.</li>
</ul>
<p>To prevent future disruption, I have implemented both mitigations outlined in this helpful ServerFault answer! https://serverfault.com/a/291202 regrets_for_not_using_ubuntu++;”</p>
<ul>
<li>2021-09-23 21:28:31Z fire: https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot-vrm/issues/23 👍 (1)</li>
<li>2021-09-23 09:02:30Z lyuma: in terms of ui, is VisualScript good?</li>
<li>2021-09-23 09:02:13Z lyuma: “co-opting this channel to discuss the AnimationTree draft proposal &gt; https://docs.google.com/document/d/1mkGjnj8VzCJmZS2x6l6qMVvemylGR2OPYq4hF-sTPRI/edit?usp=sharing</li>
</ul>
<p>I think the overall design is great. we are wondering how to configure the variables”</p>
<ul>
<li>2021-09-22 19:42:40Z fire: VMD to VRM Dance https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/890322222042976286/2021-09-22_12-03-13.mp4 👍 (3)</li>
<li>2021-09-21 01:25:13Z fire: First draft of new updated extensions api. https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/52802 Lyuma</li>
<li>2021-09-20 23:21:50Z lyuma: Cool</li>
<li>2021-09-20 23:19:13Z fire: Chatted with Robert. Proposed design to do the import_node and import_scene APIs as a first pass for the OMI_audio_emitter extension. Can fallback to post hook.</li>
<li>2021-09-20 22:44:46Z lyuma: ImporterMeshInstance3D. Nice that is moving out of the Editor namespace, and less typing</li>
<li>2021-09-20 22:44:11Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/889643129525907546/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-09-20 19:50:39Z fire: gltfdocument extensions works I think. next steps 1) review 2) merge 3) update godot-vrm. for now. khajit needs food</li>
<li>2021-09-20 19:31:58Z fire: false success &gt;.&gt;</li>
<li>2021-09-20 16:57:12Z fire: &gt; reduz: it should only check whether its the same for vertex, normal and tangent</li>
<li>2021-09-20 12:26:23Z fire: openvr</li>
<li>2021-09-20 12:26:06Z fire: and after you compile it make sure you create a new <code>extensions_api.json</code> and copy the <code>gdnative_extensions.h</code> file into the godot-cpp of the plugin</li>
<li>2021-09-20 12:25:53Z fire: https://github.com/BastiaanOlij/godot/tree/xr_extension_return_buffers</li>
<li>2021-09-19 04:43:53Z fire: Contacted moody he wanted to get scons ninja and scons shared libraries done. there are new prs needing review</li>
<li>2021-09-19 04:33:10Z fire: Lots of headless crash bugs</li>
<li>2021-09-19 04:13:07Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/889001129877340160/unknown.png 😩 (1)</li>
<li>2021-09-19 03:23:59Z fire: Next up. rebuild GDExtension Openvr</li>
<li>2021-09-19 03:18:41Z fire: Spending some time checking CICD still works. Updated misc. See logs on pipeline https://github.com/V-Sekai/groups-gocd-pipelines/</li>
<li>2021-09-18 19:32:11Z lyuma: “Updated cluster install directions to account for the recent changes seeing remote ip; cockroachdb not from helm; and disabling eviction: https://github.com/V-Sekai/v-sekai-proposals/blob/master/docs/decisions/20200602-manage-backend-with-k3s.md”</li>
<li>2021-09-18 18:48:46Z lyuma: “Our server was down for 4 hours due to a kubernetes misconfiguration (one of the options was reverted to default by mistake when changing the network metallb options):</li>
</ul>
<p>To correct, I edited /etc/systemd/system/k3s.service and changed the ExecStart lines to:</p>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb1" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode cs code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode cs"><span id="cb1-1">ExecStart<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">=/</span>usr<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>local<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>bin<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>k3s \</span>
<span id="cb1-2">    server \</span>
<span id="cb1-3">        '<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">-</span>o' \</span>
<span id="cb1-4">        '<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>root<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/.</span><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;">kube</span><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>config' \</span>
<span id="cb1-5">        '<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">--</span><span class="kw" style="color: #003B4F;">default</span><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">-</span>local<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">-</span>storage<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">-</span>path' \</span>
<span id="cb1-6">        '<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>kube<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>pvc' \</span>
<span id="cb1-7">        '<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">--</span>disable<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">=</span>traefik' \</span>
<span id="cb1-8">        '<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">--</span>disable<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">=</span>servicelb' \</span>
<span id="cb1-9">        '<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">--</span>disable<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">=</span>flannel' \</span>
<span id="cb1-10">        '<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">--</span>disable<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">=</span>cni' \</span>
<span id="cb1-11">        '<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">--</span>kubelet<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">-</span>arg<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">=</span>eviction<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">-</span>soft<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">=</span>memory<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">.</span><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;">available</span><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">&lt;</span><span class="dv" style="color: #AD0000;">0</span><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">%,</span>imagefs<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">.</span><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;">available</span><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">&lt;</span><span class="dv" style="color: #AD0000;">0</span><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">%,</span>nodefs<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">.</span><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;">available</span><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">&lt;</span><span class="dv" style="color: #AD0000;">0</span><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">%</span>' \</span>
<span id="cb1-12">        '<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">--</span>kubelet<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">-</span>arg<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">=</span>eviction<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">-</span>hard<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">=</span>memory<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">.</span><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;">available</span><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">&lt;</span><span class="dv" style="color: #AD0000;">0</span><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">%,</span>imagefs<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">.</span><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;">available</span><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">&lt;</span><span class="dv" style="color: #AD0000;">0</span><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">%,</span>nodefs<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">.</span><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;">available</span><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">&lt;</span><span class="dv" style="color: #AD0000;">0</span><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">%</span>' \</span></code></pre></div>
<ul>
<li>2021-09-18 12:41:48Z fire: “&gt; WOW…. workarounds galore and its not pretty, and it crashes badly when you exit Godot, but OpenVR is breathing life and renders to the headset now. That means that the system at its core is working and we’re now at a stage of fixing bugs (well I still need to finish the changes to controllers).</li>
</ul>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>For OpenXR there is far more work to do because there currently isn’t any support for rendering to texture chains supplied by the plugin and I’m only about halfway through converting all the code. I plan to do more on that conversion tomorrow as I wait for things to be fixed in Godot before I can take the next steps with OpenVR.”</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>2021-09-18 12:41:23Z fire: &gt; mux</li>
<li>2021-09-18 03:58:34Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/52802</li>
<li>2021-09-18 01:04:23Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/888591247835541584/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-09-18 01:04:19Z fire: first draft design of GLT2DocumentExtensionEditor</li>
<li>2021-09-17 07:07:15Z fire: https://twitter.com/VR_Rosie/status/1438600868245426180?s=20</li>
<li>2021-09-16 16:24:13Z fire: Added https://github.com/godotengine/godot-proposals/issues/3305 and updated https://github.com/godotengine/godot-proposals/issues/3273</li>
<li>2021-09-16 06:28:45Z fire: “Lyuma Saracen When I wake up tomorrow I’m going to be hyped and implement https://hackmd.io/37S0FGw7TruwjiLIspl8vQ. I think the proposal is ready to go. Please read and comment.”</li>
<li>2021-09-15 15:58:29Z fire: https://twitter.com/bjornornorn/status/1435607551031357443?s=20 🆗 (1)</li>
<li>2021-09-15 15:57:26Z fire: “Having fun with shaders, but gotta go do errands. Trying to make the circle fit the box. Might need some help https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot/tree/ok_color”</li>
<li>2021-09-15 15:57:09Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/887728757702537247/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-09-15 00:43:01Z fire: Devise a workflow for https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/49775#issuecomment-919608377</li>
<li>2021-09-14 18:23:20Z fire: https://hackmd.io/37S0FGw7TruwjiLIspl8vQ</li>
<li>2021-09-14 17:18:20Z fire: &gt; Discussion this morning with Reduz to unify the <code>Ref&lt;GLTFDocument&gt;</code> api. &gt; &gt; - <code>load_file()</code>, <code>load_buffer()</code> that just generates the internal state, and <code>save_file</code> and <code>save_buffer</code> functions that save back the files. &gt; - <code>parse_scene(Node*)</code> generates the internal state from a Node* scene. And Node* write_scene() writes it out &gt; &gt; Expose a <code>Vector&lt;Ref&lt;GLTFDocumentExtension&gt;&gt;</code>”</li>
<li>2021-09-14 17:17:39Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/52541#issuecomment-919353368 Lyuma, Saracen, MMMaellon, Silent. Feedback requested on GLTFDocument api.</li>
<li>2021-09-14 07:23:22Z fire: Four Godot 4 prs on my list – 1) libcurl complete the pr and not be at 98% 2) core based gltf i/o 3) svg 4) cvtt</li>
<li>2021-09-13 22:44:02Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/887106377716224000/2021-09-13_15-42-22.mp4 👏 (4)</li>
<li>2021-09-13 22:33:29Z fire: https://github.com/TwistedTwigleg/Godot_GSOC_2020_Project/tree/IK_Modification_Fix Updated Skeleton Modifier example code Saracen</li>
<li>2021-09-13 19:07:30Z fire: Put https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/52541 for review again.</li>
<li>2021-09-13 19:07:11Z fire: Godot Meson updates https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/52311#issuecomment-918474496</li>
<li>2021-09-13 11:08:54Z fire: “Contacted Eron and sent demo materials. https://ifiregames.itch.io/chibifire-godot-4-custom-engine https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot-ik-tests”</li>
<li>2021-09-13 11:08:14Z fire: Can’t sleep so updated the skeleton modification demo https://github.com/godotengine/godot-demo-projects/issues/649</li>
<li>2021-09-11 17:59:00Z fire: Eron was interested in ewbik on sunday</li>
<li>2021-09-11 16:37:08Z fire: https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot-vrm/issues/22</li>
<li>2021-09-11 16:32:05Z fire: Lyuma I updated godot engine to remove PackedSceneGLTF. The changes will be posted in a bit for godot-vrm</li>
<li>2021-09-09 17:50:45Z fire: 👀 https://www.vrfocus.com/2021/09/ray-ban-stories-is-facebooks-299-entry-into-the-smart-glasses-market/</li>
<li>2021-09-08 17:24:52Z fire: Lyuma Saracen from reduz &gt; fire it looks good. We got quite a lot of demand to make the GLTF importer part of core, given it is needed for VR and other stuff, so I have the feeling we should optimize it for performance (which we should do anyway) and have an option to load actual meshes instead of EditorImporterMesh.. so that means we would need to provide a function to parse the mesh node into a scene node and the editor supplies, otherwise it uses Mesh as a default</li>
<li>2021-09-07 18:32:54Z fire: Miku Base Textures https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/884868837978288178/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-09-07 18:02:00Z fire: Miku Miku Dance now split into materials. https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/884861074648760380/unknown.png 👍 (2)</li>
<li>2021-09-07 16:39:33Z トカゲ: “fixed skinning https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/52462”</li>
<li>2021-09-07 05:53:14Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/884677671563460639/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-09-07 02:10:09Z fire: Trying to write down steps to make a V-Sekai/godot update</li>
<li>2021-09-06 00:25:10Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/884232728839606284/kaitai_mmd_pmx.zip</li>
<li>2021-09-06 00:24:45Z fire: https://github.com/kaitai-io/kaitai_struct_formats/pull/446 Lyuma Thanks to Hakanai I can now generate mmd_pmx c++/stl via <code>&amp; 'C:\Program Files (x86)\kaitai-struct-compiler\bin\kaitai-struct-compiler.bat' --cpp-standard=11 --target=cpp_stl .\3d\mmd_pmx.ksy -I=. --cpp-namespace kaitai_mmd_pmx</code> Also glb binary has a parser for read and write too. Can also do fbx!?!!!! Also tscn, scn, tres and res mikuleek (3)</li>
<li>2021-09-06 00:09:07Z トカゲ: “Child class of <code>EditorProperty</code>’s <code>read_only</code> property has been implemented correctly https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/51722” https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/884228687992594482/2021-09-06_9.07.35-1.mov 👍 (2)</li>
<li>2021-09-04 02:10:44Z fire: GLTF Skeletons</li>
<li>2021-09-04 01:30:12Z lyuma: We found an infinite recursion bug in the godot gltf exporter caused by the construction of gltf node objects from skeletons and skins. I believe the issue is treating skeletons as special objects, and if we expand skeleton bones to nodes initially that should simplify things greatly and prevent this type of bug.</li>
<li>2021-09-03 22:23:17Z fire: use vnen’s fix to replace saracen’s auto load fix</li>
<li>2021-09-03 15:36:00Z fire: If you were crashing Godot Engine when opening vrms, it’s a Nvidia driver bug. Please update.</li>
<li>2021-09-03 08:10:01Z lyuma: This was all imported using Unidot on godot 4.x (with progress bar patch :-p)</li>
<li>2021-09-03 08:09:11Z lyuma: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/883262336243216424/rin_himeji_lineup.png FeaturingDanteFromTheDevilMayCry (1)</li>
<li>2021-09-03 08:09:06Z lyuma: Fixed material searching logic for legacy materials. There are some issues with material ordering, but most scenes now import with the correct materials! https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/883262312969011250/rin_himeji_diorama2.png</li>
<li>2021-09-03 08:08:15Z lyuma: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/883262098942079026/archery_sample.png</li>
<li>2021-09-02 03:56:26Z lyuma: “Progress on Unidot Importer: I made some major fixes on binary asset deserialization: I finally figured out how padding works (short answer: flag 0x4000 adds padding after a byte or short), and fixed a crash by implementing support for Unity 4.x and earlier assets, since you never know where they will show up.</li>
</ul>
<p>Next up is parsing the texture filename mapping from FBX files to assist in material discovery, since Unity legacy materials default to lookup by texture <em>filename</em> rather than material name or texture name. Since Godot has no means for preserving the original filename on import when the files are not present, doing a fix to the FBX2glTF tool won’t quite cover my necessary usecase, so I think extracting the map in the tooling is easiest. Will probably revisit this decision later.” 👍 (4)</p>
<ul>
<li>2021-09-02 01:27:40Z fire: https://twitter.com/babylonjs/status/1433216048036122629?s=20 webgpu</li>
<li>2021-09-01 21:26:59Z fire: <hesien bugs=""></hesien></li>
<li>2021-09-01 15:39:17Z fire: Tried to get additional screenshots to work https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/52316</li>
<li>2021-09-01 14:53:33Z fire: Worked with ellenhp on a proposal on import, to extract all the vorbis packets and just decode vorbis so the imported file gets rid of the ogg container. This is to remove stb_vorbis because of its documented crashing nature. Has preapproval from reduz.</li>
</ul>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2021-09.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2021-08.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="changelog-2021-08" class="level1">
<h1>Changelog 2021-08</h1>
<ul>
<li>2021-08-31 23:04:24Z fire: Did a few hours of work learning Blender with Cleam last night. Did some testing of Tokage’s skeleton gizmo.</li>
<li>2021-08-30 17:09:35Z MMMaellon#2053 nice</li>
<li>2021-08-30 16:13:28Z Saracen: Got MMMaellon’s RenIK system compiling for 4.x now. It’s also worth noting that the new SkeletonModifierStack is now mainlined in 4.0, so my next task with this will be to port RenIK to using this system. The final step will be porting it to the new GDExtension system as that becomes more viable</li>
<li>2021-08-30 02:31:12Z fire: updated our engine + AUTHORITY changes + libcurl</li>
<li>2021-08-28 22:01:33Z fire: Left is blend shape / right is bones. https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/881297479033827388/2021-08-28_15-00-45.mp4</li>
<li>2021-08-28 21:52:02Z fire: I got dembones working. <code>./DemBones -i="Face_Geom.fbx" -a="Face_Anim.abc" --bindUpdate=2 -o="Decomposition_20_grouped_face.fbx" --nnz=8 -b=256</code> Note that the corresponding fbx is 0.01 scale while the alembic is in meters. The RMSE = 0.00433256 must be this low. Especially do not pass DemBones if the RMSE is like 3.5. Next thing is to integrate an existing 3d skeleton.</li>
<li>2021-08-28 21:28:03Z fire: Jonbonazza said he resolved the ipv6 dns problem and the last remaining steps are to get to build for all platforms. Details for a future iFire.</li>
<li>2021-08-28 06:24:28Z fire: https://twitter.com/mux213/status/1431474082885734403?s=20 🥽 (2)</li>
<li>2021-08-27 23:20:23Z fire: troubles</li>
<li>2021-08-27 23:20:17Z fire: Restoring spatial audio after ellenhp’s pr</li>
<li>2021-08-27 14:15:31Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/880817809737805824/image0.jpg</li>
<li>2021-08-27 09:17:32Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/880742820812562432/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-08-27 09:10:49Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/51985</li>
<li>2021-08-27 08:26:02Z lyuma: hosting seems to kind of work but plays constant physics sounds, so it’s likely that scenes are loading, but I can’t see anything.</li>
<li>2021-08-27 08:23:56Z lyuma: Made some further progress: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/880729330035077120/unknown.png pink (2)</li>
<li>2021-08-27 05:35:53Z lyuma: we do things because they are crazy</li>
<li>2021-08-27 05:35:15Z fire: https://pbs.twimg.com/media/E3OC-r7WQAUvy5l.jpg ⬆️ (1)</li>
<li>2021-08-27 05:26:19Z lyuma: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/880684632553705482/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-08-27 01:43:10Z fire: https://github.com/ValveSoftware/openvr/tree/master/samples/helloworldoverlay steam overlay</li>
<li>2021-08-26 20:20:03Z fire: https://thume.ca/2017/06/17/tree-diffing/ useful comparing two visual script trees or two godot engine scenes or maybe skeletons!?s</li>
<li>2021-08-26 19:21:48Z lyuma: Quilkin thread</li>
<li>2021-08-26 16:01:57Z fire: https://medium.com/embarkstudios/say-hi-to-quilkin-an-open-source-udp-proxy-88577c795204</li>
<li>2021-08-26 14:36:54Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/880460804351205386/image0.jpg</li>
<li>2021-08-26 11:44:22Z lyuma: With the Autoload ordering fix applied, groups client now gets to the loading bar and is able to fade out after loading some plugins, but ends up at a black screen without showing the menu screen.</li>
<li>2021-08-26 10:07:46Z lyuma: “Write PR to fix Autoload sort order (e.g.&nbsp;at runtime) https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/52122”</li>
<li>2021-08-26 01:30:05Z fire: Got together with CLEAM and got a schedule to work on Blender artwork. First thing is teach ourselves how to make a Virtual Market quality character. https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/880262796661624912/Artboard-11.png 👍🏿 (2)</li>
<li>2021-08-24 16:56:46Z Saracen: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/52071 gddab (3)</li>
<li>2021-08-24 16:56:45Z Saracen: GDScript 2.0 bug fixes</li>
<li>2021-08-24 16:10:48Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/879759658393403402/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-08-24 16:07:44Z fire: MaterialX gltf2 bake with https://github.com/fire/MaterialX/tree/standalone-gltf https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/879758889032253501/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-08-24 15:47:33Z fire: draft of materialx spec written https://github.com/fire/glTF/tree/materialx and draft of stand alone baker https://github.com/fire/MaterialX/tree/standalone</li>
<li>2021-08-23 16:44:55Z fire: Spent some time trying to bake the animations of the face going from 0 to 1 for Angry face on three_girl vrm and dem bones could not work. Bake blend shapes to skeletal animation. Did not succeed.</li>
<li>2021-08-22 07:59:23Z fire: remotes/bruvzg/msdf_fonts2</li>
<li>2021-08-20 19:09:33Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/44399</li>
<li>2021-08-20 19:08:25Z fire: https://github.com/vnen/godot-cpp/tree/gdnative-extensions</li>
<li>2021-08-20 08:30:17Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/51908 new MSDF Branch</li>
<li>2021-08-19 15:58:27Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/877944612508008468/2021-08-19_08-57-17.mp4</li>
<li>2021-08-19 15:37:58Z fire: https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/7645683/109620721-debe3f00-7b42-11eb-870b-c2207812a03f.mov</li>
<li>2021-08-19 15:33:20Z fire: Testing MSDF branch 2 https://github.com/bruvzg/godot/tree/msdf_fonts2.</li>
<li>2021-08-16 15:03:26Z fire: Nikumaru font: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/876843603413069884/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-08-16 14:36:27Z lyuma: Including 3d modifier?? ⭐ (2),gdbee (2),🍦 (2),🔥 (2)</li>
<li>2021-08-16 14:04:39Z fire: ik 3d is merged!!!!!</li>
<li>2021-08-14 00:04:31Z fire: Updated https://github.com/fire/looking-glass/ Godot Engine demo. The fix was making the app fullscreen</li>
<li>2021-08-14 00:00:04Z fire: Connected with Emili Yu https://ns.inria.fr/d3/CASSIE/</li>
<li>2021-08-13 23:59:33Z fire: Connected with FreeMocap https://twitter.com/JonMatthis</li>
<li>2021-08-13 06:07:51Z lyuma: “&gt; It’s coming! The Virtual Market 6 will commence in 18 hours! &gt; The opening ceremony will be held on JST 9:30 am, UTC 0:30 am, Eastern 8:30 pm. &gt; https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XrTj_-Yg7AA”</li>
<li>2021-08-13 04:21:30Z fire: https://twitter.com/Lyuma2d/status/1426005291573813249?s=20</li>
<li>2021-08-11 22:48:18Z fire: https://twitch.tv/freemocap Jon’s gonna stream tomorrow, Thursday from roughly 4-6pm (Eastern US time)</li>
<li>2021-08-11 15:37:36Z fire: For cloud and edge computing, made an iso that’ll automatically install k3s with proper keying if we reboot once manually to remove the iso. https://github.com/V-Sekai/k3s-auto-start-gitops</li>
<li>2021-08-10 22:56:35Z Saracen: Looking into this right now (https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues/47885), discussion will be on RocketChat #scripting</li>
<li>2021-08-10 19:47:41Z lyuma: Congrats!!</li>
<li>2021-08-10 19:47:30Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/49343/files merged 👏 (2)</li>
<li>2021-08-05 06:51:43Z MMMaellon#2053 that’s very exciting hype (3),gdhollidays (2)</li>
<li>2021-08-05 06:31:39Z lyuma: but this is a huge milestone for us: we can now open the project cleanly and fix stuff</li>
<li>2021-08-05 06:31:02Z lyuma: Groups project now opens on Godot 4 without errors! We’re still getting a few script errors here and there while exporting, and we see some issues related to loading openvr; and a godot bug related to extending a “res://” url might be affecting exports</li>
<li>2021-08-05 02:16:43Z lyuma: We’re still missing ports of GDNative code: godot speech and open?r</li>
<li>2021-08-05 02:16:04Z lyuma: Finished with the majority of the port of 430 gdscript files. We have builds running, though godot4 has bugs in export builds with preload() of tscn files so I’ll try changing those to regular load()</li>
<li>2021-08-05 01:14:44Z lyuma: V-Sekai in godot 4 is getting my avatars! https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/872648788672647208/unknown.png vrcExclaim (1)</li>
<li>2021-08-04 18:52:42Z fire: Wasm emulation of fedora 33 via RISCV64. Related to Stellar Mesh discussion. https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/872552648182751252/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-08-04 13:19:32Z fire: Trialing new github actions for all of our modules</li>
<li>2021-08-02 22:17:37Z fire: Next year Siggraph is in Vancouver 🇨🇦</li>
<li>2021-08-02 20:45:24Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/871856235098562621/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-08-02 20:14:08Z lyuma: Siggraph 2021 is the week of August 9 - August 13</li>
<li>2021-08-02 19:48:01Z fire: Siggraph 2021! invited to discord</li>
<li>2021-08-02 05:49:11Z fire: Worked on gltf2 export in Godot Engine master</li>
<li>2021-08-02 05:48:57Z fire: Worked with Nikitalita on visual regression testing of vulkan</li>
</ul>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2021-08.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2021-07.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="changelog-2021-07" class="level1">
<h1>Changelog 2021-07</h1>
<ul>
<li>2021-07-30 23:27:44Z fire: Update https://github.com/V-Sekai/FBX2glTF/releases/tag/v2021-06-20T0053%2B0000 with a godot 4 project</li>
<li>2021-07-30 23:27:32Z fire: Merged 3/5 prs related to gltf, colliders and RESET animation</li>
<li>2021-07-28 23:15:15Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/50964 Libcurl work from the net team</li>
<li>2021-07-27 15:10:18Z fire: / https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/869597574481449001/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-07-27 14:15:21Z fire: Working on CICD for https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot-hop-spin-dance as a preview for v-sekai 4</li>
<li>2021-07-26 00:39:45Z fire: https://tenor.com/view/fun-lies-imlovingit-portal-itwouldbefuntheysaid-gif-4842907</li>
<li>2021-07-26 00:22:35Z lyuma: ugly, but we do what we must</li>
<li>2021-07-26 00:22:31Z lyuma: I was able to resolve autoload cycles by passing references by loading them in the right order, and passing in the out-of-order (cyclic) references as constructor arguments, referencing them with a prefix instead of the autoload name</li>
<li>2021-07-26 00:21:40Z lyuma: There are still quite a few addons left, and then comes debugging</li>
<li>2021-07-26 00:21:32Z lyuma: Made good progress on porting GDScript. I have most VSK* and sar1_ classes ported: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/869011521290764298/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-07-25 20:06:18Z fire: Worked with OMI to add OMI https://github.com/M3-org/awesome-metaverse/pull/4 to the list.</li>
<li>2021-07-25 18:05:02Z Saracen: Nice!</li>
<li>2021-07-25 18:00:45Z fire: Saracen Bugfix for _File. I’m able to open vrms again</li>
<li>2021-07-23 20:10:25Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/868223549469511740/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-07-23 16:56:54Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/868174850005561374/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-07-23 16:56:33Z fire: https://twitter.com/MampelSkyliner Lyuma Trying to connect.</li>
<li>2021-07-22 19:59:57Z fire: https://youtu.be/WBGkyqYEdTU From Mark Mandel</li>
<li>2021-07-22 19:28:43Z fire: &gt; gizmo improvements are (finally) up for review 🙂 #50748</li>
<li>2021-07-22 18:17:32Z fire: Did some research on ai planners. https://gist.github.com/fire/e5fd4fd3a943b76f3f1e4e76c305af0b</li>
<li>2021-07-22 16:51:42Z fire: started moz hubs importer in godot engine master</li>
<li>2021-07-22 16:42:11Z fire: collaborated with jonb on libcurl in Godot</li>
<li>2021-07-22 00:05:41Z fire: OMI Meeting today. Debates are ongoing. No consensus.</li>
<li>2021-07-20 18:29:32Z fire: Reduz wants to merge the real_t is double PRs soon. 🎆 🎆</li>
<li>2021-07-20 00:01:16Z fire: Connected with https://twitter.com/lorenc_dan</li>
<li>2021-07-19 23:21:35Z fire: https://github.com/KhronosGroup/glTF/pull/1955</li>
<li>2021-07-19 23:01:08Z MMMaellon#2053 Have you guys messed with this engine before? Heard about it at work because Amazon made it https://o3de.org/ 👀 (1)</li>
<li>2021-07-19 19:23:28Z fire: “&gt; iFire and I broke the ice, but feel this would be best served as a series of workshops together. We created this issue in the omigroup/gltf-extensions repo to track progress. https://github.com/omigroup/gltf-extensions/issues/3”</li>
<li>2021-07-18 19:45:09Z Saracen: Put the Vket6 repo on GitLab. Right now, it’s just a straight port of the original, mostly making it work with Udon scripting, but I will explore changes which could be made for VKet6. https://gitlab.com/SaracenOne/vket6-vsk-booth/</li>
<li>2021-07-16 17:41:08Z fire: Godot Networking meeting Saracen</li>
<li>2021-07-15 23:45:34Z fire: Worked on glTF2 OMI_audio_emitter with humbletim</li>
<li>2021-07-15 06:47:10Z Saracen: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues/50471</li>
<li>2021-07-15 06:47:09Z Saracen: Logged this issue. Considering this one pretty crucial for V-Sekai’s 4.x port since the codebase heavily relies on dependent singletons</li>
<li>2021-07-14 19:22:42Z fire: W3C - OMI GLTF extension working group created</li>
<li>2021-07-14 19:22:23Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/823417508417110026/864919725301432360/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-07-14 19:21:56Z fire: materialx pr merged</li>
<li>2021-07-14 05:46:19Z fire: / /o/ &nbsp;❤️ ❤️ ❤️ https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/864744601017516042/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-07-14 03:32:32Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/864710936211750942/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-07-14 03:32:20Z fire: Saracen Lyuma We will be at this roundtable? https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/864710886093619240/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-07-14 00:40:41Z fire: https://github.com/omigroup/OMI/issues/64 gltf2 proposal</li>
<li>2021-07-13 21:05:10Z fire: Proposal for a materialx bsdf that works for gltf bsdf https://github.com/materialx/MaterialX/issues/653#issuecomment-879321877</li>
<li>2021-07-13 12:18:26Z lyuma: Beware: autoload cycles are a problem: two files cannot reference each other without breaking the cycle in some way. Currently, I have about 7 references to EntityManager commented out from the network_manager addon, or else Godot hard crashes when loading the project.</li>
<li>2021-07-13 12:16:42Z lyuma: “Pushed https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot-hop-spin-dance <code>groups_test_project</code> branch. The following addons now compile:
<ul>
<li>entity_manager</li>
<li>gd_util</li>
<li>input_manager</li>
<li>math_util</li>
<li>mesh_combiner</li>
<li>model_format</li>
<li>network_manager</li>
<li>quentincaffeino-console</li>
<li>sar1_log_manager</li>
<li>state_machine</li>
<li>static_baker</li>
<li>vsk_avatar (50% commented, must redo later)</li>
<li>vsk_vrm_avatar_tool” ✨ (1)</li>
</ul></li>
<li>2021-07-13 02:01:04Z fire: Got static!</li>
<li>2021-07-13 01:39:09Z fire: Can’t connect yet, but there’s less errors running</li>
<li>2021-07-13 01:38:21Z fire: Worked on https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot_voip_experimental</li>
<li>2021-07-11 21:54:33Z fire: https://github.com/V-Sekai/v-sekai-proposals/issues/34 Lyuma Wrote how to evaluate neural blendshapes</li>
<li>2021-07-10 20:31:09Z fire: For next week I’m going to get a build of groupx-4.x to cicd and then start iterating on “Two person floating name tags in a networked Groups 4.x with the ability to pass beachballs”. I asked my friend gameplay programmer and we determined that waiting for all the things to port to Godot Engine 4 has a high latency. I’m trying a new approach of growing the code base feature by feature as it was done originally for 3.x.</li>
<li>2021-07-10 20:22:34Z fire: Polishing https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/49645 for merge</li>
<li>2021-07-09 21:04:20Z fire: Morning Meeting done with Reduz, Catania and Lyuma about Pose in 3d</li>
<li>2021-07-07 18:40:06Z fire: Updated https://hackmd.io/C0oIi_vlRs6V8qa9ZCjxaw with the guessing “Blender edit” https://github.com/KhronosGroup/glTF-Blender-IO/pull/941</li>
<li>2021-07-07 18:39:23Z fire: We talked about how “godot pose matcher” is an ok name for the tool</li>
<li>2021-07-07 18:38:51Z Saracen: I’m going to try and build a test case for another bug in GodotPhysics and also start refactoring the avatar bone fixer from vsk_avatar into its own standalone addon with minimal dependencies.</li>
<li>2021-07-07 18:38:31Z fire: Worked with tokage on bone rolls https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1j6Sq7-Iy_P3esTILySrqVQ91Hlq4MsEiI35X_R-NaiI/edit#gid=0</li>
<li>2021-07-07 06:21:14Z fire: Merge pull request #50229 from reduz/fix-textures-not-updating Saracen Lyuma 👏 (2),pink (2)</li>
<li>2021-07-07 06:01:10Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/862211623782711306/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-07-07 06:00:30Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/598003845657788438/862209880990547968/fox_default_run.glb Fox is holding a leg.</li>
<li>2021-07-07 05:59:29Z fire: https://github.com/godot-extended-libraries/godot-fire/tree/feature/bake-reset-anim Lyuma Saracen QA testing the RESET pose baker</li>
<li>2021-07-06 18:11:18Z fire: Saracen was interested in my Hydro module.</li>
<li>2021-07-06 18:11:02Z fire: Saracen and I were interested in GridMate interest management techniques</li>
<li>2021-07-06 18:10:34Z fire: Evaluated o3de 1. GridMate as a college class !!!! 2. OIT (Transparency) 3. TressFX ??? 4. animation sync 5. behavior tree</li>
<li>2021-07-05 21:07:53Z fire: “Did some work on physics collision bugs but didn’t complete. Sent to saracen. https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot/commit/99a9f79e25f7760cb5a0990e67545d78e9dd0423”</li>
<li>2021-07-05 15:29:30Z fire: “I figured out the bug with the ewbik ui. need to separate the concept of the stored”“serialisable”” data vs the internal runtime data because the serialisable data can’t access the skeleton.”</li>
<li>2021-07-03 23:41:32Z fire: worked with eron and also seperately got the ik to not reset every solve on ewbik</li>
<li>2021-07-02 07:14:33Z fire: https://github.com/materialx/MaterialX/pull/651 Standalone material baker</li>
<li>2021-07-01 19:13:21Z fire: Vket6 booth summoning of discord here?!</li>
<li>2021-07-01 15:35:11Z fire: Poked https://github.com/SigNoz/signoz/issues/193</li>
<li>2021-07-01 14:48:52Z fire: Discussed with HumbleTim the concept of a source glb we run again as many individual solvers for the input data, if the input is solved and it passes QA, that is one that is the outputed.</li>
<li>2021-07-01 14:22:16Z fire: https://github.com/materialx/MaterialX/issues/650#issuecomment-871921261</li>
<li>2021-07-01 14:21:54Z fire: ThorVG now supports images! in svg</li>
</ul>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2021-07.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2021-06.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="changelog-2021-06" class="level1">
<h1>Changelog 2021-06</h1>
<ul>
<li><p>2021-06-30 17:31:02Z lyuma: Updated the GDScript migration script: https://github.com/V-Sekai/gd3to4/commit/bad3998a69273ba3b1172cead10363b7fda706cd</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-30 17:29:12Z lyuma: “Posted the MToon shader on the Godot Shaders page: https://godotshaders.com/shader/mtoon-shader-for-godot/”</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-30 09:27:28Z fire: Shaved some yaks to get the point of gltf2 export. Made 5 prs.</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-29 15:13:05Z fire: “Today I will work on:</p></li>
<li><p><input type="checkbox" disabled="" checked="">Expedite the SVG PR https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/49645</p></li>
<li><p><input type="checkbox" disabled="">Investigate gltf2 export https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/48947 and https://github.com/fire/godot/tree/gltf-export-02</p></li>
<li><p><input type="checkbox" disabled="">Investigate VOIP in Godot Engine outside of Godot Engine org tree”</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-28 03:02:32Z fire: Sent saracen an animation test</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-27 20:35:13Z fire: I wrote a 20 step instruction on how to save any pose as the rest pose. https://github.com/V-Sekai/blue-tin-fox-models/blob/master/characters/blender-save-pose-as-rest-pose.md</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-27 04:34:09Z fire: Invited a few new people this week. Say hi to LillyByte from Godot Engine Discord and mrmetaverse from OMI Group</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-24 22:57:41Z fire: https://hubs.mozilla.com/spoke/projects/new?sceneId=Rpt8DJS</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-24 22:40:50Z fire: https://github.com/MozillaReality/hubs-blender-exporter https://github.com/KhronosGroup/glTF/pull/1400 Lyuma</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-24 21:34:56Z fire: Talked with Robert from OMI about the useful of a spatial audio emitter extension. There’s also a microsoft and a mozilla hub implementation for spatial audio node in wav?, mp3? or ogg? . He had unfinished business with the extension namespace of hubs and wanted to split it.</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-23 00:19:33Z lyuma: “https://github.com/V-Sekai-godot-hop-spin-dance Don’t get your hopes up quite yet: A lot of the lower level dependencies for scene packing and t-posing are not converted yet, but the tool scripts work now, so it’s a start :-p” 🔥 (1)</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-23 00:19:07Z lyuma: Worked with fire to get the avatar conversion tool updated, using the high level vsk_avatar vsk_vrm_avatar_tool modules: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/857052116593803284/unknown.png</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-22 23:48:06Z lyuma: mux says they also keep hitting this issue. they also made the connection to set_name() interestingly</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-22 23:47:51Z lyuma: after a day of debuggin, Saracen got a reproduction project here: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues/49843</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-22 23:22:17Z fire: Another day. Implement vrm quaternion format from lox9973 from ShaderMotion to move godot VRMs</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-22 21:00:23Z fire: We ported the avatar T-Poser to the point the menu popup shows and checkpointed, then concluded for lunch. Multiple modules were ported.</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-22 20:56:35Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot-proposals/issues/2903 Lyuma wrote a proposal</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-22 17:33:46Z fire: “Did a 5 minute design for libcurl in Godot Engine. Use https://github.com/OpenAPITools/openapi-generator/tree/master/modules/openapi-generator/src/main/resources/C-libcurl as a template.”</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-22 17:22:01Z fire: Defined a mantra for groups: <code>Presence with custom avatars and custom worlds.</code></p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-22 15:55:37Z fire: Updated https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/49645 CICD Passes https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/856925406166515722/unknown.png</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-21 13:24:31Z fire: Did I do this wrong? A vs B cs C https://imgsli.com/NTgzMDk/1/2</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-21 12:40:26Z fire: Good news, the gd_util, math_util and vsk_avatar plugin enables. Now to test it.</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-21 03:30:21Z fire: Updated godot-vrm to latest master. https://github.com/V-Sekai/godot-vrm/tree/master 👍 (1)</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-20 23:44:26Z Saracen: More fixes to be compatible with the latest master branch. Also making more bug reports for serious issues I encounter 🐛 (1),👍 (1)</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-20 20:29:37Z fire: It’s pretty slow like 7 seconds</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-20 20:29:23Z fire: &gt; RGBA Max error: 77 RMSE: 1.55 PSNR 44.34 dB</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-20 20:29:22Z fire: # bc7_enc_rdo</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-20 20:29:01Z Saracen: Wow, the existing one is already pretty fast. Good job!</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-20 20:28:33Z fire: “# Current (1 thread) RGBA Max error: 57 RMSE: 0.85 PSNR 49.57 dB CVTT 1024x1024 total time: 1.55 secs # Previous (1 thread) RGBA Max error: 28 RMSE: 0.43 PSNR 55.53 dB CVTT 1024x1024 total time: 35.68 secs”</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-20 20:28:32Z fire: https://github.com/fire/godot/tree/faster-cvtt Lyuma Saracen Faster BPTC compression.</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-19 22:42:58Z Saracen: I think I managed to fix the performance issue. It was a badly ported coroutine calling a heavy function continually. Still some issues with pathfinding and abilities not executing, but it’s at least actually functioning now.</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-19 19:22:18Z Saracen: Further fixes, there’s workarounds now for the tool I wrote to extract root motion. Two of the notable bugs I’ve discovered are ConfigFile.load returning random values and the fact that there doesn’t seem to be implicit casting between String and StringName. Want to create some example projects for this. It’s also worth noting that while Amethyst is close to being functional now, it’s running OBSCENELY slow at the moment. 🦥 (1)</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-19 18:01:49Z Saracen: Some more progress on the Amethyst port</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-19 07:45:39Z fire: Can now export blends to gltf2 and save as an artifact. Also installs vrm plugin.</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-19 07:45:30Z fire: https://github.com/V-Sekai/blue-tin-fox-models</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-19 00:16:57Z fire: Discussed with Saracen and Acquaintances to add a female mannequin to add coloured characters.</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-18 21:01:16Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/49717</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-18 20:15:22Z lyuma: That’s a bug with shadow mesh actually</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-18 20:14:42Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues/49706</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-18 10:29:49Z lyuma: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/855393862876790804/avp_living.jpg</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-18 10:28:07Z lyuma: There are still things missing, of course: for example, some materials like the walls use a custom shader with nonstandard property names… but the overall scene structure does get imported! 👏 (3)</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-18 10:27:51Z lyuma: I’m proud to announce that Unidot Importer was finally able to import the “Vol. 6” AirBnB House without any major errors! https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/855393367545085983/unknown.png</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-17 22:53:22Z fire: 2 visual script godot engine prs merged</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-17 17:01:09Z fire: !!!</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-17 16:59:42Z Saracen: I pushed an experimental branch of Amethyst designed to work in 4.0 upstream to a new branch. The behaviour tree is still broken though.</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-16 23:24:26Z fire: https://github.com/fire/godot/tree/bc7enc_rdo Updated</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-16 23:23:49Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/49669 Lyuma not sure if it’s the crash</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-16 17:55:57Z fire: OMI meeting notes.</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-16 17:54:58Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/854781112055234561/June_16th_2021_OMI_Meeting.pdf</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-16 17:52:52Z fire: ThorVG made bugfixes to my failure code.</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-16 07:18:45Z fire: Got very sidetracked. Also implemented ThorVG to compare.</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-14 16:30:44Z fire: Code review from Blender for faster baking performance</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-14 16:30:09Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/49601 PR for SVG module.</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-13 02:50:12Z fire: Woke up with a dream. openseeface as a body tracker. https://github.com/you-win/openseeface-gd/issues/16</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-13 02:44:32Z fire: Related to the comic book reader idea for vr</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-13 02:39:39Z fire: I wrote a SVG module for godot engine https://github.com/sammycage/lunasvg/issues/47</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-12 22:26:57Z fire: I think I’m breaking lyuma’s server</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-12 22:26:21Z fire: Godot Engine 4 and Groups 4.x builds have been flowing for the last day or so on itchio</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-12 22:16:36Z fire: Chatted with youwin with Lyuma and did work on gdopenseeface, gltf and godot-vrm</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-12 22:16:09Z fire: Chatted with https://twitter.com/CaptainProton42 and joined a few repositories</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-11 22:07:17Z fire: https://github.com/Tom94/tev !</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-11 03:46:06Z lyuma: Updated the <code>@export</code> fix for a third time. It’s amazing how many different ways there are to fix bit operations on a single line of code</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-11 03:45:26Z lyuma: Updated shader_improvements_meta_3.x branch for latest 3.x godot so someone could try SCSS (I want to keep it for historical purposes). I’m not going to update 4.x because it’s in flux and too much churn with renames to keep anything working</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-11 03:44:54Z lyuma: Found a bug in MToon, related to a line of code that flips the normal if it’s pointing backwards from the view direction (you can see this if you look at an MToon face with custom normals from a sharp direction).</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-10 22:56:30Z fire: Restoring the CICD builds for godot 4. I did the changes, but currently verifying that it builds on Groups 4.x and then I’ll try github.com/godotengine@master</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-10 03:11:20Z fire: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/845777129605300255/852383622606094346/unknown.png https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/845777129605300255/852383560882323487/unknown.png I tested compute graphs earlier. This is is the important part. I can now start a github action, start a kubernetes server, start a argo server, start an alpine linux image, have a whale message a hello world and then save it as a file and have it be download as a github artifact</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-09 20:50:29Z lyuma: “I tried baking lighting in the”“AirBNB”” and ran into this error: &gt; WARNING: Inconsistency found in triangulation while building BSP, probe interpolation quality may degrade a bit. &gt; at: LightmapGI::_compute_bsp_tree (scene\3d_gi.cpp:460) &gt; &gt; Jfons informed me it is an issue with separating tetrahedrons. The scene has 2641 light probes so there’s probably something suspect there. I’ll have to look into it further. I think I have an idea: we have to make sure there are probes above and below to form a complete tetrahedron”</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-09 20:49:09Z lyuma: “Summary about lightmap UV problem: Mesh scale &amp; import scale matters when dealing with lightmaps. There were bugs reading the scale, but now that is fixed and the issue with losing polygons will only happen on triangles with 1e-7 edge length in world space.</p></li>
</ul>
<p>The issue with removing mesh edges still exists, in theory, but in practice it seems unlikely so let’s wait and see if it shows up in the wild and then we can take another look”</p>
<ul>
<li>2021-06-09 18:09:18Z lyuma: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/852248004215570432/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-06-09 18:07:18Z lyuma: Due to a glitch in Godot’s etcpak implementation, I had to use BPTC texture compression. It took 3-4 hours to compress all the textures :-p (I can’t use uncompressed textures because VRAM isn’t free and I don’t own a 3090) godette (1)</li>
<li>2021-06-09 18:06:25Z lyuma: so it’s bound to improve further. it’s pretty fun seeing this place come together</li>
<li>2021-06-09 18:06:04Z lyuma: A lot of objects are missing material assignments due to naming rules (for example ” - ” or ” #” in filenames</li>
<li>2021-06-09 18:05:39Z lyuma: I know it’s not the v-sekai 4.x port but I took a break from it to work a bit more on fixing import issues: https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/852247085931298896/unknown.png</li>
<li>2021-06-09 13:44:28Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/49458#event-4864988341 Lyuma</li>
<li>2021-06-08 16:57:57Z fire: Blank screen</li>
<li>2021-06-08 16:57:53Z fire:</li>
</ul>
<p><code>OpenVR: initialising OpenVR context Application in scene (normal) mode. Main OpenVR interface has been initialized Main render models interface has been initialized. Exec path: C:/Users/XXXX/Desktop/groups-4.x/godot/bin</code></p>
<ul>
<li>2021-06-08 16:04:42Z fire: Fell asleep doing Quat and Transform3D renames</li>
<li>2021-06-08 12:25:39Z fire: “Need to build godot, then copy the generated files for GDNative. <code>--gdnative-generate-json-api api.json</code> <code>--gdnative-generate-json-builtin-api builtin_api.json</code>”</li>
<li>2021-06-08 10:22:22Z fire: Lyuma Openvr godot 4</li>
<li>2021-06-08 10:21:49Z fire: fire build godot using:</li>
</ul>
<p>godot#49301</p>
<p>Then build the plugin with:</p>
<p>godot_openvr#123</p>
<p>Make sure to use vnens godot-cpp and copy all the gdnative headers and stuff into place from your godot build”</p>
<ul>
<li><p>2021-06-08 02:36:48Z fire: Lyuma Saracen MMMaellon https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/836651615532482611/851650948467916810/unknown.png 👍 (1),VRDude (2)</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-07 19:44:27Z fire: https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/49401 PR</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-07 07:02:52Z fire: Made a release of FBX2glTF https://github.com/V-Sekai/FBX2glTF/releases/tag/v2021-06-07T06_5500_00</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-06 16:20:36Z fire: ✨ Silent’s Birthday Party. Cake, Shrine and 15 fps. Someone mentioned there was a guest list of a hundred.</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-04 14:59:40Z fire: My first Blender pr. ✨ https://developer.blender.org/D11502/new/ 👍 (1)</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-03 22:27:31Z fire: Lyuma lots of things changed today. Including Transform -&gt; Transform3D</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-03 14:55:15Z fire: Meeting done.</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-03 12:59:57Z fire: “Lyuma Saracen MMMaellon PR review meeting on https://meet.jit.si/godot-pr-review in 5 min, everyone welcome. We’ll bikeshed about”“breaks compat”” PRs for 4.0 (mostly renaming stuff in the API, etc.)”</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-03 04:47:29Z fire: ”</p>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb1" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode cpp code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode cpp"><span id="cb1-1">diff <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">--</span>git a<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>source<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>blender<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>io<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>collada<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>AnimationExporter<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">.</span>cpp b<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>source<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>blender<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>io<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>collada<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>AnimationExporter<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">.</span>cpp</span>
<span id="cb1-2">index <span class="dv" style="color: #AD0000;">73952</span><span class="er" style="color: #AD0000;">b06bc9</span><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">.</span><span class="fl" style="color: #AD0000;">.3679</span><span class="er" style="color: #AD0000;">dd090b4</span> <span class="dv" style="color: #AD0000;">100644</span></span>
<span id="cb1-3"><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">---</span> a<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>source<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>blender<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>io<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>collada<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>AnimationExporter<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">.</span>cpp</span>
<span id="cb1-4"><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">+++</span> b<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>source<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>blender<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>io<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>collada<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">/</span>AnimationExporter<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">.</span>cpp</span>
<span id="cb1-5"><span class="er" style="color: #AD0000;">@@</span> <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">-</span><span class="dv" style="color: #AD0000;">100</span><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">,</span><span class="dv" style="color: #AD0000;">6</span> <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">+</span><span class="dv" style="color: #AD0000;">100</span><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">,</span><span class="dv" style="color: #AD0000;">10</span> <span class="er" style="color: #AD0000;">@@</span> <span class="dt" style="color: #AD0000;">bool</span> AnimationExporter<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">::</span>exportAnimations<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">()</span></span>
<span id="cb1-6">    openLibrary<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">();</span></span>
<span id="cb1-7"></span>
<span id="cb1-8">    BCObjectSet<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">::</span>iterator it<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">;</span></span>
<span id="cb1-9"><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">+</span></span>
<span id="cb1-10"><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">+</span><span class="er" style="color: #AD0000;">#ifdef WITH_OMP</span></span>
<span id="cb1-11"><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">+</span><span class="er" style="color: #AD0000;">#pragma omp parallel for</span></span>
<span id="cb1-12"><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">+</span><span class="er" style="color: #AD0000;">#endif</span></span>
<span id="cb1-13">    <span class="cf" style="color: #003B4F;">for</span> <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">(</span>it <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">=</span> animated_subset<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">.</span>begin<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">();</span> it <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">!=</span> animated_subset<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">.</span>end<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">();</span> <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">++</span>it<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">)</span> <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">{</span></span>
<span id="cb1-14">        Object <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">*</span>ob <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">=</span> <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">*</span>it<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">;</span></span>
<span id="cb1-15">        exportAnimation<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">(</span>ob<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">,</span> animation_sampler<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">);</span><span class="er" style="color: #AD0000;">```</span> <span class="dv" style="color: #AD0000;">15</span> minutes to <span class="dv" style="color: #AD0000;">5</span> minutes gltf2 anim <span class="kw" style="color: #003B4F;">export</span><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;">.</span></span></code></pre></div></li>
<li><p>2021-06-02 20:39:33Z fire: Lyuma Any thoughts on making Mousse a VRM? I’m stuck. Meshes are not exporting from Blender. Compiling Blender 2.93 (LTS) for debugging.</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-02 20:19:18Z fire: Wasm GDNative and Godot Engine will be evaluated in future releases https://twitter.com/nonunknown3/status/1400090487005011970?s=20</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-02 20:14:14Z fire: / Blender 2.93 is out https://www.blender.org/download/releases/2-93/ https://twitter.com/i/status/1373384489146142720</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-02 19:03:14Z fire: Worked with Lyuma with posting a comment about small and bigger than [-1, 1] weights on blend shapes. Will send it off to the rendering team and we’re punting it.</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-02 15:08:21Z fire: Spent an hour debugging gltf2 blend shapes. 💤 Conclusion, blender export bug in 2.91 (stable is 2.92)</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-01 15:03:23Z fire: lottie -&gt; zstd compressed packaged scene (online)</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-01 15:03:08Z fire: inkscape -&gt; lottie -&gt; saved in an ordered list container with zstd (all offline). <code>.cb7l</code></p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-01 14:41:05Z fire: Investigating a path where we do pdf -&gt; svg (vectors and raster images) -&gt; lottie (vectors and raster images)</p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-01 13:43:29Z fire: Finding libraries that does pdf https://github.com/reMarkable/pdfium-binaries https://pdfium.googlesource.com/pdfium/+/HEAD/docs/getting-started.md <code>pdfium page as_image</code></p></li>
<li><p>2021-06-01 06:25:26Z lyuma: https://twitter.com/VSekaiOfficial/status/1399608449101484032</p></li>
</ul>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/changelog/changelog-2021-06.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
