<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>V-Sekai - Manuals</title>
<link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:26:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/present-proposal-template.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="overcoming-v-sekai-limitations-by-documentation" class="level1">
<h1>Overcoming V-Sekai limitations by documentation</h1>
<section id="metadata" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="metadata">Metadata</h2>
<ul>
<li>Status: proposed <!-- draft | proposed | rejected | accepted | deprecated | superseded by --><br>
</li>
<li>Deciders: V-Sekai<br>
</li>
<li>Tags: V-Sekai</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-backdrop" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-backdrop">The Backdrop</h2>
</section>
<section id="the-challenge" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h2>
</section>
<section id="the-strategy" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-strategy">The Strategy</h2>
</section>
<section id="the-upside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-upside">The Upside</h2>
</section>
<section id="the-downside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-downside">The Downside</h2>
</section>
<section id="the-road-not-taken" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-road-not-taken">The Road Not Taken</h2>
</section>
<section id="the-infrequent-use-case" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-infrequent-use-case">The Infrequent Use Case</h2>
</section>
<section id="in-core-and-done-by-us" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="in-core-and-done-by-us">In Core and Done by Us?</h2>
</section>
<section id="further-reading" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="further-reading">Further Reading</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://v-sekai.org/">V-Sekai</a><br>
</li>
<li>This article is assisted by AI.</li>
</ul>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/present-proposal-template.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230903-replicate-vrm-transform.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="enabling-vrm-to-blender-conversion-with-cloud-gpus-and-replicate.com" class="level1">
<h1>Enabling VRM to Blender Conversion with Cloud GPUs and replicate.com</h1>
<section id="metadata" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="metadata">Metadata</h2>
<ul>
<li>Status: proposed</li>
<li>Deciders: V-Sekai, fire, antpb</li>
<li>Tags: V-Sekai</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-backdrop" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-backdrop">The Backdrop</h2>
<p>The VRM format is becoming increasingly popular in the field of 3D modeling and animation. It allows for easy sharing and transfer of humanoid 3D models with skeletal animations between different software applications. One such application is the Godot Engine, a popular open-source game engine.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-challenge" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h2>
<p>Currently, developers working with VRM files in Godot Engine face difficulties when trying to convert these files to Blender format for further editing or manipulation. Manual conversion processes can be time-consuming and error-prone.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-strategy" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-strategy">The Strategy</h2>
<p>The proposed strategy for enabling VRM to Blender conversion involves leveraging the computational power of cloud GPUs provided by replicate.com. By running a GPU-accelerated Blender instance, developers can perform an identity operation on the VRM input, converting it to Blender format. This simplifies the process of converting VRM files to Blender format.</p>
<p>To convert VRM files to Blender format, developers can follow these steps:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Install the necessary libraries or plugins in Blender that support the VRM format.</li>
<li>Leverage replicate.com’s infrastructure to spin up a GPU-accelerated Blender instance.</li>
<li>Develop a script or tool that takes the VRM file as input and sends it to the GPU-accelerated Blender instance via a REST interface.</li>
<li>In the GPU-accelerated Blender instance, use the installed libraries or plugins to perform the conversion from VRM to Blender format.</li>
<li>Also use Blender to perform the conversion from Blender to VRM/GLTF format.</li>
</ol>
<p>This strategy streamlines the workflow for developers, saving time and improving collaboration between designers and developers. The use of cloud GPUs and replicate.com’s infrastructure ensures fast and efficient conversion processes.</p>
<p>Additionally, this strategy can also be extended to other software applications or websites that can utilize a REST interface, allowing developers working with VRM files to convert them to Blender format seamlessly, regardless of the software they are using.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-upside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-upside">The Upside</h2>
<ul>
<li>Streamlined workflow: Developers can easily convert VRM files to Blender format, opening up a wide range of editing and manipulation possibilities.</li>
<li>Time-saving: The use of cloud GPUs and replicate.com’s infrastructure ensures fast and efficient conversion processes.</li>
<li>Improved collaboration: The ability to work with VRM models in both Godot Engine and Blender facilitates collaboration between designers and developers.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-downside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-downside">The Downside</h2>
<ul>
<li>Development effort and expertise: Creating the necessary library or plugin may require significant technical knowledge in both the Godot Engine and VRM format.</li>
<li>Compatibility issues: Different versions of FBX or GLB files may introduce compatibility challenges during the conversion process.</li>
<li>Maintenance challenges: Keeping up with future updates to the Godot Engine and VRM specifications may require ongoing effort.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-road-not-taken" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-road-not-taken">The Road Not Taken</h2>
<p>We considered developing a web application, but it was deemed to have heavy engineering costs.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-infrequent-use-case" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-infrequent-use-case">The Infrequent Use Case</h2>
<p>While the proposed solution focuses on streamlining VRM to Blender conversion for the Godot Engine ecosystem, the same concept can be extended to other software applications or websites that can utilize a REST interface. This allows developers working with VRM files to convert them to Blender format seamlessly, regardless of the software they are using. The use of cloud GPUs and replicate.com’s infrastructure still ensures fast and efficient conversion processes.</p>
</section>
<section id="in-core-and-done-by-us" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="in-core-and-done-by-us">In Core and Done by Us?</h2>
<p>Fire knows the way.</p>
</section>
<section id="further-reading" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="further-reading">Further Reading</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://v-sekai.org/">V-Sekai</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/vrm-c/vrm-specification/tree/master/specification/VRMC_vrm_animation-1.0">VRM Animation Specification</a></li>
<li><a href="https://replicate.com/fire/v-sekai.mediapipe-labeler">Replicate - Cloud GPU Toy</a></li>
</ul>
<p>This article is assisted by AI.</p>
<p>Is there anything else I can assist you with?</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230903-replicate-vrm-transform.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230831-fixing-upload-limits.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="enhancing-map-uploads" class="level1">
<h1>Enhancing Map Uploads</h1>
<section id="metadata" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="metadata">Metadata</h2>
<ul>
<li>Status: accepted</li>
<li>Deciders: V-Sekai, fire, Scipi</li>
<li>Tags: V-Sekai</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-backdrop" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-backdrop">The Backdrop</h2>
<p>V-Sekai is facing limitations in its Elixir uro backend when uploading maps, specifically related to the Godot Engine scenes. These limitations are believed to be caused by a restriction in the Waffles library.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-challenge" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h2>
<p>The challenge at hand is to address the arbitrary limitations imposed by the Waffles library on the Godot Engine scenes during map uploads in the Elixir uro backend of V-Sekai.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-strategy" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-strategy">The Strategy</h2>
<p>To overcome this challenge, we propose patching the Waffles library in collaboration with our new contributor.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-upside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-upside">The Upside</h2>
<p>By patching the Waffles library, we can effectively remove the limitations on the Godot Engine scenes and improve the functionality of map uploads in V-Sekai.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-downside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-downside">The Downside</h2>
<p>It is important to consider any potential downsides or risks associated with patching the Waffles library. Further analysis and testing may be required to ensure compatibility and stability.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-road-not-taken" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-road-not-taken">The Road Not Taken</h2>
<p>Alternative solutions to address the limitations have been explored, but patching the Waffles library appears to be the most viable option.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-infrequent-use-case" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-infrequent-use-case">The Infrequent Use Case</h2>
<p>This limitation impacts the specific use case of map uploads in the Elixir uro backend, and may not affect other functionalities in V-Sekai.</p>
</section>
<section id="in-core-and-done-by-us" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="in-core-and-done-by-us">In Core and Done by Us?</h2>
<p>As a core functionality of V-Sekai, addressing the limitations in the Godot Engine scenes during map uploads is a task that should be done by our team.</p>
</section>
<section id="further-reading" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="further-reading">Further Reading</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://v-sekai.org/">V-Sekai</a></li>
<li>This article is assisted by AI.</li>
<li>https://github.com/V-Sekai/v-sekai-game/issues/68</li>
</ul>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230831-fixing-upload-limits.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230831-fixing-menus.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="fix-menus-in-game" class="level1">
<h1>Fix menus in-game</h1>
<section id="metadata" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="metadata">Metadata</h2>
<ul>
<li>Status: accepted</li>
<li>Deciders: V-Sekai</li>
<li>Tags: V-Sekai</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-backdrop" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-backdrop">The Backdrop</h2>
</section>
<section id="the-challenge" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h2>
<p>The menus in-game are unable to capture events from the VR controllers.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-strategy" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-strategy">The Strategy</h2>
<p>Debug the <code>on_pointer_pressed</code> function as it is not working correctly due to an issue with <code>Transform3D.xform_inv</code>. The current implementation mimics mouse input, but it fails to translate global positions correctly. Review the <code>global_to_viewport</code> function and ensure it returns the correct value for <code>local_at</code>.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-upside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-upside">The Upside</h2>
<p>Fixing the menus will enable players to interact with them using VR controllers, enhancing the user experience.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-downside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-downside">The Downside</h2>
<p>Fixing the menus may require significant code changes, introducing potential bugs or conflicts that need proper testing to ensure stability.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-road-not-taken" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-road-not-taken">The Road Not Taken</h2>
<p>Exploring alternative input systems specifically designed for VR controllers could be considered, but it may involve rewriting a large portion of the menu code and potentially introducing new dependencies.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-infrequent-use-case" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-infrequent-use-case">The Infrequent Use Case</h2>
<p>This fix targets players using VR controllers to interact with the menus. Players without VR controllers will not be affected.</p>
</section>
<section id="in-core-and-done-by-us" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="in-core-and-done-by-us">In Core and Done by Us?</h2>
<p>Yes, this issue falls within our core development responsibilities, and we will take ownership of fixing the menus.</p>
</section>
<section id="further-reading" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="further-reading">Further Reading</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://v-sekai.org/">V-Sekai</a></li>
<li>This article is assisted by AI.</li>
</ul>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230831-fixing-menus.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230830-generating-v-sekai-worlds.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="expanding-worlds" class="level1">
<h1>Expanding Worlds</h1>
<section id="metadata" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="metadata">Metadata</h2>
<ul>
<li>Status: proposed</li>
<li>Deciders: V-Sekai</li>
<li>Tags: V-Sekai</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>V-Sekai is a virtual reality (VR) platform that offers users the opportunity to immerse themselves in virtual worlds. However, there are certain limitations that hinder the overall user experience. This proposal aims to address these limitations by proposing specific areas for improvement within V-Sekai.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-challenge" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h2>
<p>V-Sekai currently faces several limitations, including non-functional menus in VR mode and a limited number of available worlds. These challenges affect the usability and variety of experiences for the users. To overcome these challenges and enhance the V-Sekai user experience, we must prioritize and focus on one area for improvement.</p>
<section id="proposed-solutions" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="proposed-solutions">Proposed Solutions</h3>
<p>We propose focusing on <strong>Generating More Worlds</strong> as the first step towards enhancing V-Sekai. By creating new VR worlds within V-Sekai, users will have a wider range of experiences to explore. This involves designing and implementing new environments to expand the options available. With more worlds to choose from, users will have increased engagement and longer sessions within the V-Sekai platform.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="the-strategy" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-strategy">The Strategy</h2>
<p>To generate more worlds for V-Sekai, we will follow a comprehensive strategy that includes the following steps:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>Identify User Preferences</strong>: Understand the target audience and their preferences. Research popular VR themes, genres, and settings to get an idea of what users would enjoy.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Design New Environments</strong>: Use 3D modeling software like Blender or Unity to design new virtual environments for V-Sekai. Consider creating diverse worlds like fantasy realms, futuristic cities, natural landscapes, or historical settings.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Implement Interactive Elements</strong>: Make the new worlds interactive by adding objects, characters, and elements that users can engage with. This can include non-playable characters (NPCs), puzzles, hidden items, or mini-games within each world.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Test and Refine</strong>: Conduct thorough testing to ensure the new worlds are visually appealing, optimized for performance, and provide a seamless VR experience. Gather user feedback and make necessary improvements based on their suggestions.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Integrate with V-Sekai</strong>: Once the new worlds are ready, integrate them into the V-Sekai platform. Ensure they are easily accessible through the menus or navigation system within V-Sekai’s VR interface.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Release and Promote</strong>: Launch the updated version of V-Sekai with the newly generated worlds. Promote the release through various channels, such as social media, gaming forums, Virtual Reality communities, and V-Sekai’s official website.</p></li>
</ol>
<p>By following this strategy, we will not only address the current limitations but also create an engaging and immersive VR experience for V-Sekai users.</p>
</section>
<section id="upsides" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="upsides">Upsides</h2>
<ul>
<li>Increased user engagement: The availability of more worlds will provide users with greater options to explore, leading to longer sessions and increased immersion in V-Sekai.</li>
<li>Expanded user base: With a wider range of experiences, V-Sekai will attract new users who are looking for diverse VR environments.</li>
<li>Positive word-of-mouth: Satisfied users will share their experiences with others, generating positive reviews and recommendations for V-Sekai.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="downsides" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="downsides">Downsides</h2>
<ul>
<li>Development complexity: Creating new worlds requires significant effort and resources, including 3D modeling, programming, and testing. This may lead to increased development time and costs.</li>
<li>Upfront investment: Generating more worlds will require upfront investment in terms of design, implementation, and integration with V-Sekai.</li>
<li>User feedback and iteration: Continuous user feedback is crucial to refine and improve the new worlds. This iterative process may extend the development timeline.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-road-not-taken" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-road-not-taken">The Road Not Taken</h2>
<p>An alternative solution that was considered was <strong>Integrating Backend Services</strong>. This would involve improving the backend infrastructure of V-Sekai to enhance scalability, performance, and reliability. However, after careful consideration, we prioritize generating more worlds as it directly addresses user experience limitations and provides tangible benefits in terms of user engagement and appeal.</p>
</section>
<section id="in-core-and-done-by-us" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="in-core-and-done-by-us">In Core and Done by Us?</h2>
<p>The generation of more worlds is within the core capabilities of our team at V-Sekai. We have experienced 3D designers, developers, and testers who are skilled in creating immersive VR environments. Therefore, we are confident in our ability to execute this proposed solution effectively and efficiently.</p>
</section>
<section id="further-reading" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="further-reading">Further Reading</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://v-sekai.org/">V-Sekai</a></li>
<li>This article is assisted by AI.</li>
</ul>
<p>If you have any further questions or need clarification on any aspect of this proposal, please feel free to ask.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230830-generating-v-sekai-worlds.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230830-better-object-pick.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="improving-vr-experience" class="level1">
<h1>Improving VR Experience</h1>
<section id="metadata" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="metadata">Metadata</h2>
<ul>
<li>Status: proposed</li>
<li>Deciders: V-Sekai</li>
<li>Tags: V-Sekai</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>V-Sekai is a virtual reality (VR) platform that offers users the opportunity to immerse themselves in virtual worlds. However, there are certain limitations that hinder the overall user experience. This documentation aims to address these limitations by proposing specific areas for improvement within V-Sekai.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-challenge" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h2>
<p>V-Sekai currently faces several limitations, including non-functional menus in VR mode and a limited number of available worlds. To overcome these challenges and enhance the user experience, we must prioritize and focus on one area for improvement.</p>
<section id="proposed-solutions" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="proposed-solutions">Proposed Solutions</h3>
<p><strong>Improving Object Pickup and Menus</strong>: Enhancing object pickup mechanics and menus can make interactions within V-Sekai more intuitive and user-friendly. This may include refining controls, feedback mechanisms for object pickup, and finding alternative methods to access menus while in VR mode.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="the-strategy" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-strategy">The Strategy</h2>
<p>To ensure efficient use of time and resources, it is advisable to choose one area to focus on and strive to complete it within a two-week timeframe. This focused approach allows for significant progress in improving V-Sekai.</p>
</section>
<section id="upsides" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="upsides">Upsides</h2>
<p>By addressing these limitations, V-Sekai can offer a more seamless and immersive VR experience. Improving object pickup and menus will enhance user interactions, making them more intuitive and user-friendly. This will ultimately result in a more engaging and enjoyable experience for V-Sekai users.</p>
</section>
<section id="downsides" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="downsides">Downsides</h2>
<p>Given the limited timeframe, it may not be possible to address all the identified limitations simultaneously. Additionally, the complexity of refining object pickup mechanics and menus may present challenges in achieving substantial improvements within the two-week timeframe. It’s important to carefully assess the scope and feasibility of the proposed enhancements before committing to the timeframe.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-road-not-taken" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-road-not-taken">The Road Not Taken</h2>
<p>While focusing on improving object pickup and menus is recommended for the given timeframe, it’s important to acknowledge that there are other potential areas for improvement. Exploring options such as expanding the variety of worlds, integrating backend services, or optimizing performance can be considered in future iterations of V-Sekai.</p>
</section>
<section id="in-core-and-done-by-us" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="in-core-and-done-by-us">In Core and Done by Us?</h2>
<p>The development team at V-Sekai should primarily handle the implementation and integration of the chosen improvement. However, collaborative efforts involving developers, designers, and user experience experts may be necessary to ensure the improvements align with the overall vision and goals of V-Sekai.</p>
</section>
<section id="further-reading" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="further-reading">Further Reading</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://v-sekai.org/">V-Sekai</a></li>
<li>This article is assisted by AI.</li>
</ul>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230830-better-object-pick.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230830-better-backend-services.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="integrating-backend-services" class="level1">
<h1>Integrating Backend Services</h1>
<section id="metadata" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="metadata">Metadata</h2>
<ul>
<li>Status: proposed</li>
<li>Deciders: V-Sekai</li>
<li>Tags: V-Sekai</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>V-Sekai is a virtual reality (VR) platform that offers users the opportunity to immerse themselves in virtual worlds. However, there are certain limitations that hinder the overall user experience. This documentation aims to address these limitations by proposing specific areas for improvement within V-Sekai.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-challenge" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h2>
<p>V-Sekai currently faces several limitations, including non-functional menus in VR mode and a limited number of available worlds. To overcome these challenges and enhance the user experience, we must prioritize and focus on one area for improvement.</p>
<section id="proposed-solutions" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="proposed-solutions">Proposed Solutions</h3>
<p><strong>Exploring Backend Services Integration</strong>: Integrating V-Sekai with backend services can enhance the platform’s features and capabilities. This could involve incorporating external APIs or services to provide additional resources and functionalities.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="the-strategy" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-strategy">The Strategy</h2>
<p>To ensure efficient use of time and resources, it is advisable to choose one area to focus on and strive to complete it within a two-week timeframe. This focused approach allows for significant progress in improving V-Sekai.</p>
</section>
<section id="upsides" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="upsides">Upsides</h2>
<p>By addressing these limitations, V-Sekai can be transformed into a more immersive and engaging VR platform. Enhancing menus and object pickup mechanics, expanding the variety of worlds, or integrating backend services can greatly enhance the overall user experience for users.</p>
</section>
<section id="downsides" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="downsides">Downsides</h2>
<p>Given the limited timeframe, it may not be possible to address all the identified limitations simultaneously. Prioritizing one area means that other aspects may need to wait for future improvements. Additionally, the complexity of the chosen area may present challenges in achieving substantial improvements within the two-week timeframe.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-road-not-taken" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-road-not-taken">The Road Not Taken</h2>
<p>While focusing on one area is recommended for the given timeframe, it’s important to acknowledge that there are other potential avenues for improvement. Exploring options such as performance optimization, improving UI design, or implementing additional features can be considered in future iterations of V-Sekai.</p>
</section>
<section id="in-core-and-done-by-us" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="in-core-and-done-by-us">In Core and Done by Us?</h2>
<p>The development team at V-Sekai should primarily handle the implementation and integration of the chosen improvement. However, collaborative efforts, involving developers, designers, and technical writers, are essential for documenting the enhancements.</p>
</section>
<section id="further-reading" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="further-reading">Further Reading</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://v-sekai.org/">V-Sekai</a></li>
<li>This article is assisted by AI.</li>
</ul>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230830-better-backend-services.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230829-omifest-2023.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="omifest-2023---the-call" class="level1">
<h1>OMIFest 2023 - The Call</h1>
<section id="metadata" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="metadata">Metadata</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Status</strong>: Proposed</li>
<li><strong>Deciders</strong>: OMIGroup, Fire, Indiebio</li>
<li><strong>Tags</strong>: OMIGroup, V-Sekai</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="context" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="context">Context</h2>
<section id="the-backdrop" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-backdrop">The Backdrop</h3>
<p>OMIFest 2023 is an online event set against the backdrop of a rapidly evolving digital landscape. As virtual reality and augmented reality technologies become more accessible, there’s an increasing need for platforms that allow artists, tinkerers, hackers, players, and professionals to showcase their talents and collaborate in a digital environment.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-challenge" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h3>
<p>The challenge is to create an event that not only celebrates these individuals but also encourages conversation and collaboration within our community. We aim to build a webpage on the OMI website for more information and updates about this online event.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="decision" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="decision">Decision</h2>
<section id="the-strategy" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-strategy">The Strategy</h3>
<p>Our strategy is to host a series of monthly events leading up to the main event in October 2024. Each month we will focus on different aspects of the event, such as building the vehicle, avatars, textures, scenery, and workshops on content creation.</p>
<section id="goals-sorted-by-ease" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="goals-sorted-by-ease">Goals (Sorted by ease)</h4>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Research</strong>: Held in conjunction with an academically minded in-person conference.</li>
<li><strong>Assets, protocols, and specification testing</strong>: Build assets and test protocols to ensure interoperability.</li>
<li><strong>Community Celebration</strong>: Celebrate with the global community in a digital setting.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="who-can-participate" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="who-can-participate">Who Can Participate?</h4>
<p>This online event is open to everyone. Individuals, teams, corporate members, community groups, anyone and everyone can submit an entry. Registration will be required for our information, and some moderation may be required, but everyone is welcome.</p>
</section>
<section id="event-features-sorted-by-ease" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="event-features-sorted-by-ease">Event Features (Sorted by ease)</h4>
<ol type="1">
<li>Notice boards for help needed, job board, find a team etc</li>
<li>Limited poster advertising</li>
<li>Music</li>
<li>Booths for nonprofit, education, community organisations</li>
<li>Metaverse library/blockbuster to find how-to guides, videos, etc</li>
<li>Thrift shop for free stuff</li>
<li>Market for assets</li>
<li>Junk yard for abandoned assets</li>
<li>Portals to other worlds</li>
<li>Assets that are created remain in the world</li>
<li>Scenery around the parade</li>
<li>Parade with floats</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="cost-to-enter" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="cost-to-enter">Cost to Enter</h4>
<p>It is free to register and submit assets. The event will be free to attend. Some aspects and mini events may require payment.</p>
</section>
<section id="sponsorship" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sponsorship">Sponsorship</h4>
<p>We are open to sponsorships for this online event. More details will be provided soon.</p>
</section>
<section id="calendar-of-events" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="calendar-of-events">Calendar of Events</h4>
<p>Here is a rough schedule of our monthly events:</p>
<table class="table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Date</th>
<th>Topic</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>August 2023</td>
<td>Content sharing workshop</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>September 2023</td>
<td>Making a basic vehicle</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>October 2023</td>
<td>Making an avatar</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>November 2023</td>
<td>Making textures</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>December 2023</td>
<td>Making scenery</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>January 2024</td>
<td>Music in the metaverse</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>February 2024</td>
<td>AI</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>March 2024</td>
<td>Community, public spheres</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>April 2024</td>
<td>Portals</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>May 2024</td>
<td>(repeat the above?)</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>June 2024</td>
<td>Use art to explore data</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>July 2024</td>
<td>Real world challenge</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</section>
</section>
<section id="the-upside" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-upside">The Upside</h3>
<p>The upside of this online event is that it provides a platform for individuals from various backgrounds to showcase their talents, learn from each other, and collaborate on projects. It also helps in promoting the use of VR/AR technologies and encourages innovation in this field.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-downside" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-downside">The Downside</h3>
<p>The downside could be the potential logistical challenges involved in organizing such a large-scale online event. There might also be issues related to ensuring fair participation and dealing with intellectual property rights.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-road-not-taken" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-road-not-taken">The Road Not Taken</h3>
<p>An alternative approach could have been to organize smaller, more frequent online events throughout the year. However, we decided to go with a larger annual event to create more impact and allow participants enough time to prepare.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-infrequent-use-case" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-infrequent-use-case">The Infrequent Use Case</h3>
<p>While the event is designed to cater to a wide range of participants, there might be some who might not be able to participate due to lack of access to necessary technology or skills. We plan to address this by providing resources and learning materials to help them get started.</p>
</section>
<section id="in-core-and-done-by-us" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="in-core-and-done-by-us">In Core and Done by Us?</h3>
<p>Yes, the event is being organized by us, OMIGroup, in collaboration with V-Sekai. We are responsible for planning, coordinating, and executing aspects of the event. The success of such a large-scale online event relies on the collective efforts of many individuals and organizations.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="references" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="references">References</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://omigroup.org/">OMIGroup</a></li>
<li><a href="https://v-sekai.org/">V-Sekai</a></li>
<li><a href="https://hackmd.io/@indiebio/metaverse-float-parade">Metaverse Float Parade</a></li>
<li>This article is assisted by AI.</li>
</ul>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230829-omifest-2023.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230824-subdiv-for-lods.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="use-opensubdiv-for-lods" class="level1">
<h1>Use opensubdiv for lods</h1>
<section id="metadata" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="metadata">Metadata</h2>
<ul>
<li>Status: proposed <!-- draft | proposed | rejected | accepted | deprecated | superseded by --><br>
</li>
<li>Deciders: V-Sekai, fire</li>
<li>Tags: V-Sekai</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-backdrop" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-backdrop">The Backdrop</h2>
<p>Creators want more. Players want more. The platform can only support a limited amount of content.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-challenge" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h2>
<p>The challenge lies in optimizing the content to fit within the platform’s limitations without compromising on the quality and detail.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-strategy" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-strategy">The Strategy</h2>
<p>Use OpenSubdiv to increase detail, which can then be reduced through Godot Engine’s LOD (Level of Detail) scheme. This allows for high-quality models that are optimized for performance.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-upside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-upside">The Upside</h2>
<p>The upside is that this approach allows for more detailed models while still maintaining good performance.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-downside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-downside">The Downside</h2>
<p>The downside is that it requires additional processing to create the LOD models, which could potentially slow down the development process.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-road-not-taken" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-road-not-taken">The Road Not Taken</h2>
<p>An alternative approach would have been to manually create lower detail models for use in less demanding scenarios. However, this would require significantly more work from the creators.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-infrequent-use-case" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-infrequent-use-case">The Infrequent Use Case</h2>
<p>This strategy might not be beneficial for very simple models or scenes where the level of detail is not a significant factor.</p>
</section>
<section id="in-core-and-done-by-us" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="in-core-and-done-by-us">In Core and Done by Us?</h2>
<p>Yes, this strategy is implemented in the core of our platform and maintained by us.</p>
</section>
<section id="further-reading" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="further-reading">Further Reading</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://v-sekai.org/">V-Sekai</a><br>
</li>
<li>This article is assisted by AI.</li>
</ul>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230824-subdiv-for-lods.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230823-speech-to-blendshapes.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="developing-a-unified-model-for-speech-to-facial-shape-generation-using-outlines-library" class="level1">
<h1>Developing a Unified Model for Speech-to-Facial Shape Generation Using Outlines 〰 Library</h1>
<section id="metadata" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="metadata">Metadata</h2>
<ul>
<li>Status: proposed</li>
<li>Deciders: V-Sekai</li>
<li>Tags: V-Sekai</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-backdrop" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-backdrop">The Backdrop</h2>
<p>V-Sekai is embarking on a project that translates speech into corresponding facial shapes for virtual reality applications. This process eliminates the need for a face camera and leverages the <code>SpeechEncoderDecoderModel</code> from Hugging Face’s Transformers library for comprehensive speech recognition.</p>
<p>The SpeakingFaces dataset, a collection from 142 diverse subjects, will be utilized for this project. The dataset is accessible via the server of the Institute for Smart Systems and Artificial Intelligence (ISSAI) under the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.</p>
<p>Outlines 〰, a neural text generation library, will also play a crucial role in this project. It offers robust prompting primitives, separates the prompting from the execution logic, and is compatible with all models. It interfaces with models through the next-token logits and can be used with API-based models as well.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-challenge" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h2>
<p>The primary challenge lies in developing a model capable of generating text and blendshapes simultaneously from the same input speech using the Outlines 〰 library.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-strategy" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-strategy">The Strategy</h2>
<p>The proposed strategy involves creating a custom model that accepts speech as input and outputs both text and blendshapes. This unified model would incorporate a shared encoder to process the speech input, and a single decoder to generate the text and blendshape outputs. The Outlines 〰 library will be used to conform the output to the desired format.</p>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb1" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode python code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode python"><span id="cb1-1"><span class="im" style="color: #00769E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">from</span> outlines <span class="im" style="color: #00769E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">import</span> Outline</span>
<span id="cb1-2"><span class="im" style="color: #00769E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">from</span> transformers <span class="im" style="color: #00769E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">import</span> SpeechEncoderDecoderModel, Speech2Text2Processor, Wav2Vec2Model</span>
<span id="cb1-3"><span class="im" style="color: #00769E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">import</span> json</span>
<span id="cb1-4"></span>
<span id="cb1-5"><span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;"># Initialize the processor and encoder</span></span>
<span id="cb1-6">processor <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">=</span> Speech2Text2Processor.from_pretrained(<span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"facebook/s2t-small-librispeech-asr"</span>)</span>
<span id="cb1-7">encoder <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">=</span> Wav2Vec2Model.from_pretrained(<span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"facebook/wav2vec2-base-960h"</span>)</span>
<span id="cb1-8"></span>
<span id="cb1-9"><span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;"># Initialize the decoder</span></span>
<span id="cb1-10">decoder <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">=</span> Speech2Text2Model.from_pretrained(<span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"facebook/s2t-small-librispeech-asr"</span>)</span>
<span id="cb1-11"></span>
<span id="cb1-12"><span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;"># Initialize the unified model</span></span>
<span id="cb1-13">model <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">=</span> UnifiedSpeechEncoderDecoderModel(encoder<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">=</span>encoder, decoder<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">=</span>decoder)</span>
<span id="cb1-14"></span>
<span id="cb1-15"><span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;"># Define an outline for the model</span></span>
<span id="cb1-16">outline <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">=</span> Outline(model).to(device)</span>
<span id="cb1-17"></span>
<span id="cb1-18"><span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;"># Generate text and blendshapes</span></span>
<span id="cb1-19">generated_text, generated_blendshapes <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">=</span> outline.generate(input_speech)</span>
<span id="cb1-20"></span>
<span id="cb1-21"><span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;"># Conform to JSON schemaßß</span></span>
<span id="cb1-22">blendshapes_keys <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">=</span> [<span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"BrowInnerUp"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"BrowDownLeft"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"BrowDownRight"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"BrowOuterUpLeft"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"BrowOuterUpRight"</span>,</span>
<span id="cb1-23">                    <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"EyeLookUpLeft"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"EyeLookUpRight"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"EyeLookDownLeft"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"EyeLookDownRight"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"EyeLookInLeft"</span>,</span>
<span id="cb1-24">                    <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"EyeLookInRight"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"EyeLookOutLeft"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"EyeLookOutRight"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"EyeBlinkLeft"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"EyeBlinkRight"</span>,</span>
<span id="cb1-25">                    <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"EyeSquintRight"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"EyeSquintLeft"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"EyeWideLeft"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"EyeWideRight"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"CheekPuff"</span>,</span>
<span id="cb1-26">                    <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"CheekSquintLeft"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"CheekSquintRight"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"NoseSneerLeft"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"NoseSneerRight"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"JawOpen"</span>,</span>
<span id="cb1-27">                    <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"JawForward"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"JawLeft"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"JawRight"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthFunnel"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthPucker"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthLeft"</span>,</span>
<span id="cb1-28">                    <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthRight"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthRollUpper"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthRollLower"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthShrugUpper"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthShrugLower"</span>,</span>
<span id="cb1-29">                    <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthClose"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthSmileLeft"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthSmileRight"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthFrownLeft"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthFrownRight"</span>,</span>
<span id="cb1-30">                    <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthDimpleLeft"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthDimpleRight"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthUpperUpLeft"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthUpperUpRight"</span>,</span>
<span id="cb1-31">                    <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthLowerDownLeft"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthLowerDownRight"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthPressLeft"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthPressRight"</span>,</span>
<span id="cb1-32">                    <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthStretchLeft"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"MouthStretchRight"</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"TongueOut"</span>]</span>
<span id="cb1-33"></span>
<span id="cb1-34">output <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">=</span> {</span>
<span id="cb1-35">    <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"text"</span>: generated_text,</span>
<span id="cb1-36">    <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">"blendshapes"</span>: <span class="bu" style="color: null;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">dict</span>(<span class="bu" style="color: null;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">zip</span>(blendshapes_keys, generated_blendshapes))</span>
<span id="cb1-37">}</span>
<span id="cb1-38"></span>
<span id="cb1-39">json_output <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">=</span> json.dumps(output)</span></code></pre></div>
</section>
<section id="the-upside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-upside">The Upside</h2>
<p>Developing our own unified model for generating both text and blendshapes from speech using the Outlines 〰 library is a strategic move that provides us with greater control and customization to meet our specific needs. It not only deepens our understanding of the model, aiding in troubleshooting and improvements, but also allows us to optimize it for better performance and efficiency.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-downside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-downside">The Downside</h2>
<p>The limitation of this approach is that the <code>UnifiedSpeechEncoderDecoderModel</code>, and <code>Outline</code> are placeholders for your actual unified model classes, and outline respectively. You would need to implement these classes yourself, or find pre-trained models that suit your needs.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-road-not-taken" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-road-not-taken">The Road Not Taken</h2>
<p>Being self-reliant in maintaining and updating our model eliminates dependence on third parties, providing flexibility to make changes as needed. Moreover, it ensures seamless integration with other parts of our system.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-infrequent-use-case" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-infrequent-use-case">The Infrequent Use Case</h2>
<p>While this approach requires more initial effort, the potential for improvement and fine-tuning with our unique data sets makes it worthwhile, leading to superior results in the long run.</p>
</section>
<section id="in-core-and-done-by-us" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="in-core-and-done-by-us">In Core and Done by Us?</h2>
<p>Yes, the development and maintenance of the unified model will be done by us.</p>
</section>
<section id="further-reading" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="further-reading">Further Reading</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://v-sekai.org/">V-Sekai</a></li>
<li>This article is assisted by AI.</li>
</ul>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230823-speech-to-blendshapes.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230819-train-game.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="following-tracks-enhancing-vr-train-station-simulation-in-v-sekai-using-godot-engine" class="level1">
<h1>Following Tracks: Enhancing VR Train Station Simulation in V-Sekai using Godot Engine</h1>
<section id="metadata" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="metadata">Metadata</h2>
<ul>
<li>Status: proposed</li>
<li>Deciders: V-Sekai</li>
<li>Tags: V-Sekai, Godot Engine, VR Development</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-backdrop" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-backdrop">The Backdrop</h2>
<p>V-Sekai is a platform that specializes in VR development with the Godot engine. It’s currently facing challenges because there isn’t a test game available. The goal is to develop a minimal viable product for a train station simulator. This simulator will focus on avatar rendering, networking simulation, and parented objects in the train.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-challenge" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h2>
<p>The main problems are the need for precise controls in VR and the ability to render and network large groups of people in VR. This also includes extensive NPC tests with skeletal animation in the Godot engine for VR.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-strategy" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-strategy">The Strategy</h2>
<p>The strategy involves adding new features to V-Sekai to address these challenges:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Networking Avatar Crowds:</strong> The aim here is to develop efficient methods for networking large groups of avatars in VR. This will involve creating a system that can handle the high data traffic required for real-time interaction between numerous avatars, while maintaining performance and stability. This could be achieved by implementing advanced networking protocols and optimization techniques to ensure smooth communication between avatars without overloading the network.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="the-upside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-upside">The Upside</h2>
<p>If this strategy is implemented successfully, it could enhance the user experience in VR games developed using the Godot engine. It could also enable the creation of more diverse and complex VR environments.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-downside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-downside">The Downside</h2>
<p>This process may require significant resources and time, and there might be technical limitations.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-road-not-taken" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-road-not-taken">The Road Not Taken</h2>
<p>An alternative could have been to use a different game engine that already supports these features. However, this wouldn’t contribute to the improvement of the Godot engine.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-infrequent-use-case" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-infrequent-use-case">The Infrequent Use Case</h2>
<p>These improvements might not benefit all types of games or developers. Their relevance depends on the specific needs and goals of each project.</p>
</section>
<section id="in-core-and-done-by-us" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="in-core-and-done-by-us">In Core and Done by Us?</h2>
<p>V-Sekai’s expertise in VR development and understanding of its challenges make it well-suited to lead these improvements. By doing so, V-Sekai can align with developer needs, contribute to the open-source Godot engine, and help build a stronger community around it.</p>
<p>Despite requiring effort and resources, the potential benefits for both V-Sekai and the wider Godot engine community make it a worthwhile investment.</p>
</section>
<section id="further-reading" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="further-reading">Further Reading</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://v-sekai.org/">V-Sekai</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-proposals/discussions/4233">Godot Engine Proposal Discussion</a></li>
</ul>
<p>This article is assisted by AI.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230819-train-game.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230813-mixer-broadcaster-into-membrane-framework copy.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="rewriting-mixer-broadcaster-into-membrane-framework-pipelines" class="level1">
<h1>Rewriting Mixer Broadcaster Into Membrane Framework Pipelines</h1>
<section id="metadata" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="metadata">Metadata</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Status</strong>: Rejected</li>
<li><strong>Deciders</strong>: V-Sekai<br>
</li>
<li><strong>Tags</strong>: V-Sekai, Elixir, Membrane Framework, Multiplayer Blender</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-backdrop" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-backdrop">The Backdrop</h2>
<p>Ubisoft’s mixer broadcaster code has been the only available solution for handling multiplayer Blender. However, it has its limitations when it comes to scalability and real-time performance. This proposal aims to rewrite the code using Elixir and the Membrane Framework.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-challenge" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h2>
<p>The main challenge is to translate the existing code into Elixir while maintaining the functionality and improving upon the limitations of the current system. This includes ensuring that the new code can handle larger volumes of users and provide real-time updates without lag or delay.</p>
</section>
<section id="strategy" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="strategy">Strategy</h2>
<pre class="mermaid"><code>graph LR
  A[Ubisoft's Mixer Broadcaster Code] --&gt; B[Elixir &amp; Membrane Framework Code]
  C[No Authentication] --&gt; D[GitHub OAuth 2.0 Login]
  E[No Database] --&gt; F[Khepri Database Library]</code></pre>
<p>This strategy leverages Elixir and the Membrane Framework’s unique features, uses the Khepri database library for data management, and implements GitHub login using OAuth 2.0 protocol for single sign-on.</p>
<p>Here are the key steps:</p>
<ul>
<li><p><strong>Codebase</strong>: Transition from Ubisoft’s Mixer Broadcaster Code to Elixir &amp; Membrane Framework Code, tracked in a version control system.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Dependencies</strong>: Declare and isolate dependencies explicitly, avoiding reliance on system-wide packages.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Config</strong>: Store configuration (including GitHub OAuth 2.0 Login credentials) in the environment, not in the code.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Backing Services</strong>: Replace in-memory data persistence with Khepri Database Library, attached as a backing service.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Build, Release, Run</strong>: Strictly separate these stages, facilitated by the Elixir &amp; Membrane Framework Code.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Processes</strong>: Execute application as one or more stateless processes, storing needed state in the Khepri database.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Port Binding</strong>: Export services via port binding, making the application self-contained.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Concurrency</strong>: Scale out the application via the process model, allowing for handling increased load.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Disposability</strong>: Aim for fast startup and graceful shutdown to maximize robustness.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Dev/Prod Parity</strong>: Keep development, staging, and production environments as similar as possible.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Logs</strong>: Treat logs as event streams, handled by the executing environment.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Admin Processes</strong>: Run any needed one-off administrative tasks in an identical environment as the regular long-running processes of the app.</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-upside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-upside">The Upside</h2>
<p>By rewriting the code in Elixir, using the Membrane Framework, and implementing the Khepri database library, we can expect improved scalability and real-time performance. This will allow for more users to use the system simultaneously without experiencing delays or lags. Additionally, the fault-tolerance feature of Elixir will ensure that the system remains operational even when errors occur.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-downside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-downside">The Downside</h2>
<p>Rewriting the code will require time and resources. There may also be a learning curve for developers who are not familiar with Elixir, the Membrane Framework, and the Khepri database library.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-road-not-taken" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-road-not-taken">The Road Not Taken</h2>
<p>An alternative approach would have been to optimize the existing code instead of rewriting it. However, this would not have addressed the inherent limitations of the current system.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-infrequent-use-case" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-infrequent-use-case">The Infrequent Use Case</h2>
<p>In cases where the number of users is low and real-time updates are not critical, the current system may still be sufficient. However, as the user base grows and the demand for real-time updates increases, the need for a more scalable and efficient system becomes apparent.</p>
</section>
<section id="in-core-and-done-by-us" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="in-core-and-done-by-us">In Core and Done by Us?</h2>
<p>Yes, the rewriting of the code will indeed be done by us as we also maintain the uro backend services.</p>
</section>
<section id="further-reading" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="further-reading">Further Reading</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://v-sekai.org/">V-Sekai</a><br>
</li>
<li><a href="https://elixir-lang.org/">Elixir</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.membraneframework.org/">Membrane Framework</a></li>
<li><a href="https://hex.pm/packages/khepri">Khepri Database Library</a></li>
</ul>
<p><em>This article is assisted by AI.</em></p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230813-mixer-broadcaster-into-membrane-framework copy.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230813-blender-runner-into-membrane-framework.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="transitioning-to-membrane-framework-pipelines-with-json-rpc-blender-runner" class="level1">
<h1>Transitioning to Membrane Framework Pipelines with JSON-RPC Blender Runner</h1>
<section id="metadata" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="metadata">Metadata</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Status</strong>: Proposed</li>
<li><strong>Deciders</strong>: V-Sekai<br>
</li>
<li><strong>Tags</strong>: V-Sekai, Elixir, Membrane Framework, Multiplayer Blender, JSON-RPC</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="backdrop" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="backdrop">Backdrop</h2>
<p>The current solution for handling multiplayer Blender has its limitations when it comes to scalability and real-time performance. To address these issues, we propose a new approach that leverages Elixir and the Membrane Framework. This will involve rewriting the code and introducing a JSON-RPC Blender runner.</p>
<section id="character-posing" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="character-posing">Character Posing</h3>
<p>In this new approach, character posing will be handled in real-time and shared across multiple clients. This means that any changes made to a 3D model by one user will be immediately reflected on all other connected clients. This feature will enhance the collaborative experience and allow users to interact with the same 3D models simultaneously.</p>
</section>
<section id="world-sharing" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="world-sharing">World Sharing</h3>
<p>The state of the world, including objects, lighting, camera position, etc., will also be synchronized across all clients. This ensures that all users are experiencing the same environment, further enhancing the sense of immersion and collaboration.</p>
</section>
<section id="procedural-generation" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="procedural-generation">Procedural Generation</h3>
<p>We will introduce procedural generation techniques to create unique and dynamic environments. These generated worlds will be shared across all clients, ensuring that each user’s experience is not only immersive but also unique and engaging.</p>
</section>
<section id="grease-pencil-sharing" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="grease-pencil-sharing">Grease Pencil Sharing</h3>
<p>Any drawings or annotations made using the Grease Pencil tool will be visible to all clients. This allows for collaborative sketching and planning, making it easier for teams to communicate their ideas visually.</p>
</section>
<section id="json-rpc-blender-runner" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="json-rpc-blender-runner">JSON-RPC Blender Runner</h3>
<p>To facilitate efficient communication with Blender, we’ll implement a JSON-RPC Blender runner. This will allow us to send commands to Blender and receive responses in a structured and standardized format. This feature will streamline the process of interacting with Blender, making it more efficient and user-friendly.</p>
<p>By implementing these features, we aim to improve the scalability and real-time performance of our multiplayer Blender solution. This will lead to a more immersive and collaborative experience for our users.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="the-challenge" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h2>
<p>The main challenge is to translate the existing code into Elixir while maintaining the functionality and improving upon the limitations of the current system. This includes ensuring that the new code can handle larger volumes of users and provide real-time updates without lag or delay.</p>
</section>
<section id="strategy" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="strategy">Strategy</h2>
<pre class="mermaid"><code>graph LR
  A[Current Code] --&gt; B[Elixir &amp; Membrane Framework Code]
  C[No Authentication] --&gt; D[GitHub OAuth 2.0 Login]
  E[No Database] --&gt; F[Khepri Database Library]
  G[Blender Runner] --&gt; H[JSON-RPC Blender Runner]
  I[Triangle Only] --&gt; J[Airlocks for Environment Translation]</code></pre>
<p>This strategy leverages Elixir and the Membrane Framework’s unique features, uses the Khepri database library for data management, implements GitHub login using OAuth 2.0 protocol for single sign-on, introduces a JSON-RPC Blender runner for improved communication with Blender, and focuses on the use of triangles (a polygon with 3 vertices) and “Airlocks” for environment translation.</p>
<p>Here are the key steps:</p>
<ul>
<li><p><strong>Codebase</strong>: Transition from the current code to Elixir &amp; Membrane Framework Code, tracked in a version control system.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Dependencies</strong>: Declare and isolate dependencies explicitly, avoiding reliance on system-wide packages.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Config</strong>: Store configuration (including GitHub OAuth 2.0 Login credentials) in the environment, not in the code.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Backing Services</strong>: Replace in-memory data persistence with Khepri Database Library, attached as a backing service.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Build, Release, Run</strong>: Strictly separate these stages, facilitated by the Elixir &amp; Membrane Framework Code.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Processes</strong>: Execute application as one or more stateless processes, storing needed state in the Khepri database.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Port Binding</strong>: Export services via port binding, making the application self-contained.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Concurrency</strong>: Scale out the application via the process model, allowing for handling increased load.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Disposability</strong>: Aim for fast startup and graceful shutdown to maximize robustness.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Dev/Prod Parity</strong>: Keep development, staging, and production environments as similar as possible.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Logs</strong>: Treat logs as event streams, handled by the executing environment.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Admin Processes</strong>: Run any needed one-off administrative tasks in an identical environment as the regular long-running processes of the app.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Blender Runner</strong>: Implement a JSON-RPC Blender runner to facilitate efficient communication with Blender.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Triangle Only</strong>: This principle ensures that only triangles (polygons with 3 vertices) are used in the graphical representation. This simplifies the rendering process and reduces computational complexity.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Airlocks</strong>: Use airlocks to translate the remote environment to the local environment. This allows for seamless interaction between different parts of the system while maintaining isolation and security.</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-upside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-upside">The Upside</h2>
<p>By rewriting the code in Elixir, using the Membrane Framework, implementing the Khepri database library, introducing a JSON-RPC Blender runner, focusing on the use of triangles, and employing the “Airlocks” principles, we can expect improved scalability and real-time performance. This will allow for more users to use the system simultaneously without experiencing delays or lags. Additionally, the fault-tolerance feature of Elixir will ensure that the system remains operational even when errors occur.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-downside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-downside">The Downside</h2>
<p>Rewriting the code will require time and resources. There may also be a learning curve for developers who are not familiar with Elixir, the Membrane Framework, the Khepri database library, JSON-RPC, the concept of using triangles in graphics, and “Airlocks”.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-road-not-taken" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-road-not-taken">The Road Not Taken</h2>
<p>An alternative approach would have been to optimize the existing code instead of rewriting it. However, this would not have addressed the inherent limitations of the current system.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-infrequent-use-case" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-infrequent-use-case">The Infrequent Use Case</h2>
<p>In cases where the number of users is low and real-time updates are not critical, the current system may still be sufficient. However, as the user base grows and the demand for real-time updates increases, the need for a more scalable and efficient system becomes apparent.</p>
</section>
<section id="in-core-and-done-by-us" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="in-core-and-done-by-us">In Core and Done by Us?</h2>
<p>Yes, the rewriting of the code will indeed be done by us as we also maintain the backend services.</p>
</section>
<section id="further-reading" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="further-reading">Further Reading</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://v-sekai.org/">V-Sekai</a><br>
</li>
<li><a href="https://elixir-lang.org/">Elixir</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.membraneframework.org/">Membrane Framework</a></li>
<li><a href="https://hex.pm/packages/khepri">Khepri Database Library</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.jsonrpc.org/">JSON-RPC</a></li>
</ul>
<p><em>This article is assisted by AI.</em></p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230813-blender-runner-into-membrane-framework.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230812-vsekai-update-process.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="update-v-sekai-game-engine-procedure" class="level1">
<h1>Update V-Sekai game engine procedure</h1>
<section id="metadata" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="metadata">Metadata</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Status:</strong> proposed</li>
<li><strong>Deciders:</strong> V-Sekai</li>
<li><strong>Tags:</strong> V-Sekai</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-backdrop" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-backdrop">The Backdrop</h2>
<p>V-Sekai is an open-source project that aims to create a virtual world. However, it has some limitations that need to be addressed to improve its performance and user experience.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-challenge" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h2>
<p>The main challenge is to update the V-Sekai game engine to enhance its features and fix existing issues.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-strategy" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-strategy">The Strategy</h2>
<p>Here are the steps we propose to take:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Update the Godot Engine fork with git assembler.</li>
<li>Release the fork to the godot engine branch.</li>
<li>Update the V-Sekai-game engine commit hash.</li>
<li>Check the built V-Sekai-game binaries on Github.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="the-upside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-upside">The Upside</h2>
<p>Updating the game engine will provide better performance, improved features, and a more enjoyable user experience.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-downside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-downside">The Downside</h2>
<p>The downside could be potential bugs or issues that might arise during the update process. It may also require additional resources and time to implement the updates.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-road-not-taken" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-road-not-taken">The Road Not Taken</h2>
<p>There might be other solutions or strategies that were considered but not chosen for this particular challenge. These could be documented here for future reference.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-infrequent-use-case" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-infrequent-use-case">The Infrequent Use Case</h2>
<p>This section can be used to discuss any infrequent use cases that might arise from implementing this decision.</p>
</section>
<section id="in-core-and-done-by-us" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="in-core-and-done-by-us">In Core and Done by Us?</h2>
<p>This section can be used to discuss whether this decision is core to the project and whether it should be implemented by us or outsourced to another team.</p>
</section>
<section id="further-reading" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="further-reading">Further Reading</h2>
<p>For more information about V-Sekai, you can visit their <a href="https://v-sekai.org/">official website</a>.</p>
<p><em>This article is assisted by AI.</em></p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230812-vsekai-update-process.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230812-unmerge-and-merge-procedure-source-code-tree.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="procedure-to-unmerge-and-then-merge-solves-a-v-sekai-source-code-broken-tree" class="level1">
<h1>Procedure to unmerge and then merge solves a V-Sekai source code broken tree</h1>
<section id="metadata" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="metadata">Metadata</h2>
<ul>
<li>Status: proposed</li>
<li>Deciders: V-Sekai</li>
<li>Tags: V-Sekai</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-backdrop" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-backdrop">The Backdrop</h2>
<p>The V-Sekai source code tree has been broken due to an unsuccessful merge. This has resulted in a halt in the development process, causing delays in project timelines.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-challenge" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h2>
<p>The main challenge is to unmerge the broken tree and then successfully merge it again. This requires careful analysis of the code and understanding the root cause of the initial failed merge.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-strategy" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-strategy">The Strategy</h2>
<p>We use a tool called Git Assembly which makes reapplying branches on master easy. Here’s the strategy:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Identify the commit hash where the merge went wrong.</li>
<li>Remove the item from the Git Assembler.</li>
<li>Analyze the code and identify the conflicts that caused the merge to fail.</li>
<li>Resolve the conflicts manually.</li>
<li>Fix the branch.</li>
<li>Reapply the branch on master using Git Assembly.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="the-upside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-upside">The Upside</h2>
<p>By following this strategy, we can potentially fix the broken source code tree without losing any significant work. This will allow us to resume the development process and meet our project deadlines.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-downside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-downside">The Downside</h2>
<p>The process of unmerging and merging can be time-consuming and complex. If not done correctly, it may lead to further issues in the codebase.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-road-not-taken" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-road-not-taken">The Road Not Taken</h2>
<p>An alternative approach could have been to abandon the current branch and start a new one from the last known good state. However, this would mean losing all the changes made after the last good state.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-infrequent-use-case" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-infrequent-use-case">The Infrequent Use Case</h2>
<p>This procedure is not commonly used as merges usually go smoothly. It’s only needed when a merge results in a broken source code tree.</p>
</section>
<section id="in-core-and-done-by-us" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="in-core-and-done-by-us">In Core and Done by Us?</h2>
<p>Yes, this procedure is core to our operations and is performed by our team.</p>
</section>
<section id="further-reading" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="further-reading">Further Reading</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://v-sekai.org/">V-Sekai</a></li>
<li>This article is assisted by AI.</li>
</ul>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230812-unmerge-and-merge-procedure-source-code-tree.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230812-gocd-agent-setup.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="configuring-gocd-agents-in-v-sekai" class="level1">
<h1>Configuring GoCD Agents in V-Sekai</h1>
<section id="metadata" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="metadata">Metadata</h2>
<ul>
<li>Status: proposed <!-- draft | proposed | rejected | accepted | deprecated | superseded by --></li>
<li>Deciders: V-Sekai</li>
<li>Tags: V-Sekai</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-backdrop" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-backdrop">The Backdrop</h2>
<p>V-Sekai is a platform that requires regular configuration of GoCD agents. This process can be time-consuming and prone to errors if not done correctly.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-challenge" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h2>
<p>The challenge is to configure the GoCD agents after a restart of the host machine. This involves accessing the GoCD server, navigating to the Agents page, enabling new agents, configuring agent resources, assigning environments, and saving changes.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-strategy" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-strategy">The Strategy</h2>
<p>The strategy is to follow a step-by-step guide to ensure that all the necessary configurations are made correctly. This includes:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Accessing the GoCD Server</li>
<li>Navigating to the Agents Page</li>
<li>Enabling New Agents</li>
<li>Configuring Agent Resources</li>
<li>Assigning Environments</li>
<li>Saving Changes</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="the-upside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-upside">The Upside</h2>
<p>By following this guide, users can ensure that their GoCD agents are configured correctly and ready to run jobs. This can save time and reduce the risk of errors.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-downside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-downside">The Downside</h2>
<p>The downside is that this process needs to be repeated every time the host machine is restarted. However, this is a necessary step to ensure that the GoCD agents function correctly.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-road-not-taken" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-road-not-taken">The Road Not Taken</h2>
<p>An alternative approach could be to automate this process using scripts or other automation tools. However, this would require additional technical expertise and may not be feasible for all users.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-infrequent-use-case" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-infrequent-use-case">The Infrequent Use Case</h2>
<p>In some cases, users may need to configure additional settings or use different resources and environments. These cases will require additional steps and may not be covered by this guide.</p>
</section>
<section id="in-core-and-done-by-us" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="in-core-and-done-by-us">In Core and Done by Us?</h2>
<p>Yes, this guide was created by us and is part of our core documentation.</p>
</section>
<section id="further-reading" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="further-reading">Further Reading</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://v-sekai.org/">V-Sekai</a></li>
<li>This article is assisted by AI.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="example-configuration" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="example-configuration">Example configuration</h2>
<table class="table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Agent Type</th>
<th>Resources</th>
<th>Environments</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>gocd-agent-59dbf9989-vp4d66</td>
<td>linux, mingw5</td>
<td>development, itch-fire</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>gocd-agent-dind-96575468d4-s29l2</td>
<td>dind</td>
<td>development, itch-fire</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>gocd-agent-59dbf9989-cczqj</td>
<td>linux, mingw5</td>
<td>development, itch-fire</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>gocd-agent-59dbf9989-p6vs5</td>
<td>linux, mingw5</td>
<td>development, itch-fire</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>gocd-agent-59dbf9989-t4ckd</td>
<td>linux, mingw5</td>
<td>development, itch-fire</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>gocd-agent-dind-96575468d4-b6gq9</td>
<td>dind</td>
<td>development, itch-fire</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Please note that the actual resources and environments will vary based on your specific setup.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230812-gocd-agent-setup.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230812-constraint-all-bones.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="constrain-the-entire-godot-humanoid-skeleton" class="level1">
<h1>Constrain the entire Godot Humanoid Skeleton</h1>
<section id="metadata" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="metadata">Metadata</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Status:</strong> proposed</li>
<li><strong>Deciders:</strong> V-Sekai, fire</li>
<li><strong>Tags:</strong> V-Sekai</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-backdrop" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-backdrop">The Backdrop</h2>
<p>The current Godot humanoid skeleton system lacks proper constraints for all bones, specifically in terms of rotation swing and rotation twist limits. This has led to issues when trying to move parts of the skeleton such as the head or legs towards the torso.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-challenge" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h2>
<p>The challenge lies in implementing these constraints without causing other issues within the system. Some bones are not solved and should not be constrained, adding complexity to the task.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-strategy" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-strategy">The Strategy</h2>
<p>The strategy is to carefully analyze each bone and determine the appropriate constraints. This will involve a combination of swing rotation and twist rotation constraints, depending on the specific bone.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-upside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-upside">The Upside</h2>
<p>By implementing these constraints, we can improve the functionality and reliability of the Godot humanoid skeleton system. This will allow for more realistic movements and prevent system errors when moving certain parts of the skeleton.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-downside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-downside">The Downside</h2>
<p>There may be potential challenges in implementing these constraints, particularly for the unsolved bones. It will require careful testing and adjustment to ensure that the new constraints do not introduce new issues.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-road-not-taken" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-road-not-taken">The Road Not Taken</h2>
<p>An alternative would be to leave the system as it is, accepting its limitations. However, this would mean missing out on the potential improvements that could be achieved through this proposal.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-infrequent-use-case" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-infrequent-use-case">The Infrequent Use Case</h2>
<p>In some rare cases, the lack of constraints might actually be beneficial, allowing for unusual or exaggerated movements. These cases will need to be considered and potentially addressed separately.</p>
</section>
<section id="in-core-and-done-by-us" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="in-core-and-done-by-us">In Core and Done by Us?</h2>
<p>Yes, this change would be implemented in the core system by the V-Sekai team.</p>
</section>
<section id="further-reading" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="further-reading">Further Reading</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://v-sekai.org/">V-Sekai</a></li>
<li>This article is assisted by AI.</li>
</ul>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230812-constraint-all-bones.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230811-punchline-reports.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="punchline-based-reports" class="level1">
<h1>Punchline based reports</h1>
<section id="metadata" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="metadata">Metadata</h2>
<ul>
<li>Status: proposed <!-- draft | proposed | rejected | accepted | deprecated | superseded by --></li>
<li>Deciders: V-Sekai, fire</li>
<li>Tags: V-Sekai</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-backdrop" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-backdrop">The Backdrop</h2>
<p>Communication and project management within your game development team can be better.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-challenge" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h2>
<p>Using the reverse reporting style in game development, the project manager gets the most important information first, followed by supporting details.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-strategy" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-strategy">The Strategy</h2>
<section id="punch-line" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="punch-line">1. Punch Line</h3>
<p>This is where you present the facts related to the game development process. For example:</p>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb1" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode markdown code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode markdown"><span id="cb1-1">"The AI behavior for enemy characters wasn't completed on time, and we didn't start the level design for Stage 3 as planned."</span></code></pre></div>
<p>or</p>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb2" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode markdown code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode markdown"><span id="cb2-1">"Completed the character modeling as scheduled."</span></code></pre></div>
</section>
<section id="current-status" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="current-status">2. Current Status</h3>
<p>In this step, you explain how the punch line affects the game development project. For instance:</p>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb3" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode markdown code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode markdown"><span id="cb3-1">"Because of the incomplete AI behavior, the game testing has been delayed by a week."</span></code></pre></div>
</section>
<section id="next-steps" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="next-steps">3. Next Steps</h3>
<p>Here, you propose solutions to the problem if there are any. An example could be:</p>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb4" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode markdown code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode markdown"><span id="cb4-1">"I will be able to complete the AI behavior in the next four days but the level design for Stage 3 will still be behind schedule."</span></code></pre></div>
</section>
<section id="explanation" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="explanation">4. Explanation</h3>
<p>Finally, you provide the reasons behind the punch line. This is where you can give a detailed account of why things happened the way they did. For example:</p>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb5" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode markdown code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode markdown"><span id="cb5-1">"Three days' delay in AI behavior is due to an unexpected bug in the pathfinding system, and the remaining delay is due to being called to assist the graphics team with texture optimization."</span></code></pre></div>
</section>
</section>
<section id="the-upside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-upside">The Upside</h2>
<p>The upside of this strategy is that it allows for clear and concise communication within the team. It ensures that everyone is aware of the current status of the project and what needs to be done moving forward.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-downside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-downside">The Downside</h2>
<p>The downside is that it requires all team members to be diligent in their reporting. If someone fails to accurately report their progress or issues, it could lead to miscommunication and delays in the project.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-road-not-taken" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-road-not-taken">The Road Not Taken</h2>
<p>An alternative approach could have been to use traditional reporting methods, where each team member provides a detailed report of their work. However, this method can often lead to information overload and important details may get lost in the process.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-infrequent-use-case" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-infrequent-use-case">The Infrequent Use Case</h2>
<p>This strategy may not be as effective in smaller teams or projects where communication is more direct and less formal.</p>
</section>
<section id="in-core-and-done-by-us" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="in-core-and-done-by-us">In Core and Done by Us?</h2>
<p>Yes, this strategy should be implemented by us as it aligns with our goal of improving communication and project management within the team.</p>
</section>
<section id="further-reading" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="further-reading">Further Reading</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://v-sekai.org/">V-Sekai</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/2565077/i-m-ok--the-bull-is-dead.html">I’m OK; The Bull Is Dead</a></li>
<li>This article is assisted by AI.</li>
</ul>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230811-punchline-reports.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230806-v-sekai-ipad-projection-compatibility.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="v-sekai-navigation-compatibility-with-vr" class="level1">
<h1>V-Sekai Navigation Compatibility with VR</h1>
<section id="metadata" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="metadata">Metadata</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Status:</strong> Proposed</li>
<li><strong>Deciders:</strong> V-Sekai</li>
<li><strong>Tags:</strong> V-Sekai, iPad, Presentation Screen, Compatibility</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-backdrop" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-backdrop">The Backdrop</h2>
<p>We are developing a VR game that MUST be compatible with a wide range of devices. Our goal is to make our VR game accessible and enjoyable for this vast majority of users.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-challenge" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h2>
<p>The challenge is to ensure the game’s user interface and controls work seamlessly across these different display sizes and touch interfaces.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-strategy" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-strategy">The Strategy</h2>
<p>We considered two options: Virtual joystick for touchscreen devices and Navmesh and 3D navigation points. We chose the “Virtual joystick for touchscreen devices” because it addresses the core issue of ensuring compatibility with iPads and large projector screens, and it is more cost-effective.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-upside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-upside">The Upside</h2>
<ul>
<li>Improved user experience across different devices and screen sizes.</li>
<li>Increased versatility of the game, making it suitable for various applications.</li>
<li>Enhanced navigation in 3D spaces.</li>
<li>More cost-effective solution.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-downside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-downside">The Downside</h2>
<ul>
<li>Potential increase in development time and costs.</li>
<li>Additional resources for testing on different devices and screens.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-road-not-taken" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-road-not-taken">The Road Not Taken</h2>
<p>Navmeshes and 3D Navigation Points are tools used to define traversable spaces in a 3D environment. However, they might not be suitable when the spaces aren’t already defined, such as grids. Waypoints have similar limitations.</p>
<p>In Godot, any modification triggers a rebuild of the entire navigation map. If the map is large and complex, this rebuilding process can take a significant amount of time and lead to performance issues.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-infrequent-use-case" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-infrequent-use-case">The Infrequent Use Case</h2>
<p>While Navmesh and 3D Navigation Points provide an intuitive user interface for navigating 3D spaces, they might not translate well to continuous interaction on touchscreens, which is often expected by users on such devices.</p>
</section>
<section id="in-core-and-done-by-us" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="in-core-and-done-by-us">In Core and Done by Us?</h2>
<p>Yes, the decision to implement a virtual joystick for touchscreen devices was made by us, V-Sekai. This decision is at the core of our strategy to ensure compatibility with iPads and large projector screens while also being cost-effective.</p>
</section>
<section id="further-reading" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="further-reading">Further Reading</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://v-sekai.org/">V-Sekai</a></li>
<li>This article is assisted by AI.</li>
</ul>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230806-v-sekai-ipad-projection-compatibility.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230806-music-gen.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="sonic-symphony-crafting-melodies-with-machine-intelligence" class="level1">
<h1>Sonic Symphony: Crafting Melodies with Machine Intelligence</h1>
<section id="the-blueprint" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-blueprint">The Blueprint</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Status:</strong> In the works</li>
<li><strong>Masterminds:</strong> V-Sekai, fire</li>
<li><strong>Keywords:</strong> Music, AI, GPT-3, Python, Generation</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-backdrop" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-backdrop">The Backdrop</h2>
<p>As we navigate the 21st century, technology has become an inseparable part of our existence. It’s been making waves in the realm of music too. One such wave is the use of artificial intelligence (AI) to craft melodies. This blueprint proposes a method for creating music using computer algorithms.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-challenge" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h2>
<p>The mission is to create music using computer programs.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-strategy" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-strategy">The Strategy</h2>
<p>One promising strategy is to employ .ABC files. These files have proven effective in generating outputs with AI models like GPT-3. The .ABC files carry data in the header section, such as the key signature, tempo, and time signature, which can be incorporated into the prompt.</p>
<p>Alternatively, we could leverage AI models to script for us. For instance, we could ask for a Python script that composes the chromatic 7th intervals from C to B in eighth notes. The output format could be something user-friendly like Lilypond or MusicXML.</p>
<p>Here’s a sneak peek at a Python script:</p>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb1" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode python code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode python"><span id="cb1-1"><span class="kw" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">def</span> generate_chromatic_seventh_intervals():</span>
<span id="cb1-2">    notes <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">=</span> [<span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">'C'</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">'C#'</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">'D'</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">'D#'</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">'E'</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">'F'</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">'F#'</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">'G'</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">'G#'</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">'A'</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">'A#'</span>, <span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">'B'</span>]</span>
<span id="cb1-3">    intervals <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">=</span> []</span>
<span id="cb1-4"></span>
<span id="cb1-5">    <span class="cf" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">for</span> i <span class="kw" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">in</span> <span class="bu" style="color: null;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">range</span>(<span class="bu" style="color: null;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">len</span>(notes)):</span>
<span id="cb1-6">        seventh_interval <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">=</span> (i <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">+</span> <span class="dv" style="color: #AD0000;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">10</span>) <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">%</span> <span class="bu" style="color: null;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">len</span>(notes)</span>
<span id="cb1-7">        intervals.append((notes[i], notes[seventh_interval]))</span>
<span id="cb1-8"></span>
<span id="cb1-9">    <span class="cf" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">return</span> intervals</span>
<span id="cb1-10"></span>
<span id="cb1-11"><span class="bu" style="color: null;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">print</span>(generate_chromatic_seventh_intervals())</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Another feasible strategy might be to use AI models to generate Lilypond syntax. Lilypond is a robust and adaptable tool for engraving tasks of all kinds, including sheet music, complex notation, vocal music, etc. Here is an example of a simple Lilypond syntax:</p>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb2" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode lilypond code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode lilypond"><span id="cb2-1"><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">\relative c'</span> <span class="kw" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">{</span></span>
<span id="cb2-2">  c<span class="dt" style="color: #AD0000;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">4</span> d e f <span class="dv" style="color: #AD0000;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">|</span></span>
<span id="cb2-3">  g a b c <span class="dv" style="color: #AD0000;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">|</span></span>
<span id="cb2-4"><span class="kw" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">}</span></span></code></pre></div>
<p>This code will compose a sequence of eighth notes from C to C.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-road-not-taken" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-road-not-taken">The Road Not Taken</h2>
<p>During the journey to find a solution, several paths were explored and abandoned for various reasons:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>Using MIDI files:</strong> While MIDI files are a common choice for music creation, they were left behind due to their complexity and the challenge in crafting them programmatically.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Using MusicXML:</strong> Despite MusicXML being a comprehensive and widely supported format, it was abandoned due to its lengthy and intricate structure, which makes it tough to craft programmatically.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Using other music notation software:</strong> Other music notation software like Finale and Sibelius were considered but left behind due to their proprietary nature and lack of support for the programmatic generation of music.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="the-upside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-upside">The Upside</h2>
<ul>
<li>This approach will pave the way for easier music creation.</li>
<li>It will sidestep the limitations posed by the intricate structure of MusicXML.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-downside" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-downside">The Downside</h2>
<ul>
<li>There may be some hurdles when using AI models to generate Lilypond syntax.</li>
<li>Training small transformers to output syntactically correct .ABC files might pose a challenge.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="further-reading" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="further-reading">Further Reading</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://gwern.net/gpt-2-music">Sample .ABC files</a></li>
<li><a href="https://lilypond.org/doc/v2.24/Documentation/notation/index">Lilypond Notation Reference</a></li>
<li><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37016049">Ask HN: AI that produces sheet music for practice?</a></li>
</ul>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/decisions/20230806-music-gen.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
