<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>V-Sekai - Manuals</title>
<link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/demo_to_game.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/demo_to_game.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 04:55:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/demo_to_game/design_process.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="biomimicry-design-process" class="level1">
<h1>Biomimicry Design Process</h1>
<section id="step-1-define" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="step-1-define">Step 1: Define</h2>
<p>The first step in the biomimicry design process is to define the problem or opportunity that you want your design to address.</p>
<section id="a.-frame-your-challenge" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a.-frame-your-challenge">a. Frame Your Challenge</h3>
<p>Give a simple explanation of the impact you want to have. This is not what you want to make, but what you want your design to achieve or do.</p>
</section>
<section id="b.-consider-context" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="b.-consider-context">b. Consider Context</h3>
<p>Describe some of the contextual factors that are important to the challenge. This could include stakeholders, location conditions, resource availability, etc.</p>
</section>
<section id="c.-take-a-systems-view-and-look-for-potential-leverage-points" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="c.-take-a-systems-view-and-look-for-potential-leverage-points">c.&nbsp;Take a Systems View and Look for Potential Leverage Points</h3>
<p>Think about the system surrounding the problem (or opportunity) you are designing for. What interactions and relationships are part of its context? What are the system boundaries and connections to other systems?</p>
</section>
<section id="d.-phrase-your-challenge-as-a-question" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="d.-phrase-your-challenge-as-a-question">d.&nbsp;Phrase Your Challenge as a Question</h3>
<p>Using the information above, phrase your challenge as a question: How might we __? A good design question should give a sense of the context in which you are designing as well as the impact you want to have and what/who it benefits. Your question should be somewhat open-ended to ensure you haven’t jumped to conclusions about what you are designing.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="step-2-biologize" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="step-2-biologize">Step 2: Biologize</h2>
<p>Analyze the essential functions and context your design challenge must address. Reframe them in biological terms, so that you can “ask nature” for advice. The goal of this step is to arrive at one or more “How does nature…?” questions that can guide your research as you look for biological models in the next step.</p>
</section>
<section id="step-3-discover" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="step-3-discover">Step 3: Discover</h2>
<p>Look for natural models (organisms and ecosystems) that need to address the same functions and context as your design solution. Identify the strategies used that support their survival and success. This step focuses on research and information gathering.</p>
</section>
<section id="step-4-abstract" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="step-4-abstract">Step 4: Abstract</h2>
<p>Carefully study the essential features or mechanisms that make the biological strategy successful. Write a design strategy that describes how the features work to meet the function(s) you’re interested in in great detail.</p>
</section>
<section id="step-5-emulate-natures-lessons" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="step-5-emulate-natures-lessons">Step 5: Emulate Nature’s Lessons</h2>
<p>Once you have found a number of biological strategies and analyzed them for the design strategies you can extract, you are ready to begin the creative part—dreaming up nature-inspired solutions. Here we’ll guide you through the key activities of the Emulate step.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="note" class="level1">
<h1>Note</h1>
<p>Please remember that this is a process and it requires your active participation and feedback at every step. Let’s start with defining your challenge.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/demo_to_game/design_process.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 04:55:59 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/demo_to_game/help_write_documentation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="help-us-write-about-v-sekai" class="level1">
<h1>Help Us Write About V-Sekai</h1>
<p>We aim to create comprehensive documentation for developers and users, covering all significant features and topics. Each feature requires a dedicated page with a descriptive title and a bullet list of essential points the user needs to learn.</p>
<section id="example-topic-godot-xr" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="example-topic-godot-xr">Example Topic: Godot XR</h2>
<p>For instance, when writing about Godot XR, the user should learn:</p>
<ul>
<li>What is XR? (link to a page or provide a brief explanation)</li>
<li>What is Godot? (link to a previous page if covered, and briefly re-explain in one sentence)</li>
<li>How XR works in Godot and how our product utilizes it</li>
<li>Concrete achievements possible with this feature/knowledge</li>
<li>Limitations of the technology affecting our product</li>
</ul>
<p>Draft each page as a bullet list like this, allowing writers to understand the points to cover quickly.</p>
</section>
<section id="step-by-step-instructions" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="step-by-step-instructions">Step-by-Step Instructions</h2>
<p>For cases where users must follow steps, detail each step using straightforward language. Be consistent with verbs and phrasing to minimize cognitive load. For example:</p>
<section id="changing-game-resolution" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="changing-game-resolution">Changing Game Resolution</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Open the Project -&gt; Project Settings… menu.</li>
<li>Navigate to Display -&gt; Window in the left column. The game’s window settings appear on the right.</li>
<li>Scroll down to the resolution setting.</li>
<li>Click the numbers to change the resolution (values are in pixels).</li>
</ol>
<p>Consistently use verbs like:</p>
<ul>
<li>Click a button</li>
<li>Open a menu</li>
<li>Open a file</li>
<li>Navigate to a tab</li>
</ul>
<p>Keeping things simple, clear, and consistent makes it easier for users to concentrate on the process and remember new details.</p>


</section>
</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/demo_to_game/help_write_documentation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 04:55:59 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/demo_to_game/v_sekai_game.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="v-sekai-game-discussion" class="level1">
<h1>V-Sekai Game Discussion</h1>
<section id="gadget-mechanics" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="gadget-mechanics">Gadget Mechanics</h2>
<p>Gadgets play a crucial role in enhancing the gameplay mechanics. Each gadget provides unique abilities that can be utilized strategically within the team-based system:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Object Manipulation</strong>: Can create barriers or clear paths, aiding in strategic planning and resource management.</li>
<li><strong>Long-Range Targeting</strong>: Useful for snipers or scouts in the team, allowing them to take down targets from a distance. This is not limited to guns but includes any form of ranged gadget.</li>
<li><strong>Spell Casting</strong>: Adds complexity to combat situations. Spells can heal teammates, enhance their abilities, or damage enemies.</li>
<li><strong>Tactical Overlay</strong>: Provides real-time data about the battlefield, including enemy positions, terrain features, and resource locations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="contextual-factors-and-gameplay-mechanics" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="contextual-factors-and-gameplay-mechanics">Contextual Factors and Gameplay Mechanics</h2>
<p>The game we’re discussing is set in a post-apocalyptic future where humanity has colonized the solar system. It’s an open-world game with classless character progression. The gameplay involves both player versus player (PvP) and player versus environment (PvE) scenarios, with players forming alliances and strategizing to protect humanity from existential threats. Decisions made in the game can shape the future of the virtual universe.</p>
<p>The gameplay mechanics are designed around a team-based system, promoting players to form teams and develop strategies under the leadership of a lead. This design encourages strategic planning and effective resource management among players.</p>
</section>
<section id="player-experience" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="player-experience">Player Experience</h2>
<p>The essence of this game lies in its cooperative environment that rewards teamwork. Challenges and obstacles require a collective effort and strategy. Victory over obstacles is a shared experience, creating a sense of camaraderie among players.</p>
<p>“Skill gates” are a unique feature in the game that serve as checkpoints. These gates require players to demonstrate a specific skill they’ve learned in order to progress.</p>
<p>The level design plays a crucial role in ensuring that players acquire necessary skills and abilities before they encounter major challenges. This is achieved through various means:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Progressive Difficulty</strong>: Early levels are relatively easy, allowing players to learn the basic mechanics and controls of the game.</li>
<li><strong>Skill-Based Challenges</strong>: Obstacles that require certain skills to overcome.</li>
<li><strong>Rewarding Exploration</strong>: Hidden areas or secret paths might contain power-ups or abilities that can help players in future challenges.</li>
<li><strong>Boss Battles</strong>: Placed at the end of levels or sections, these act as tests of the skills and abilities players have gained throughout the level.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="teamwork-over-solo-play" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="teamwork-over-solo-play">Teamwork Over Solo Play</h2>
<p>In this game, teamwork is given more importance than solo play. This design choice reflects the cooperative nature of the game, where players are encouraged to form parties or teams and face challenges together.</p>
<p>The game’s cooperative gameplay design ensures that many of its missions and challenges are best tackled as a team. To support this cooperative gameplay, the game provides an option for players to form parties or teams.</p>
</section>
<section id="custom-avatars-and-voice-chat" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="custom-avatars-and-voice-chat">Custom Avatars and Voice Chat</h2>
<p>The game offers two key features that significantly enhance the player experience: custom avatars and voice chat.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Custom Avatars</strong>: Empowers players to craft unique, personalized characters, or avatars, using VRM or custom Godot scenes to represent themselves within the game world.</li>
<li><strong>Voice Chat</strong>: Provides a platform for real-time communication between players. It’s a vital tool for strategic planning and coordination among team members.</li>
</ul>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/demo_to_game/v_sekai_game.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 04:55:59 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/demo_to_game/virtual_interactions.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="emulate-natures-lessons" class="level1">
<h1>Emulate Nature’s Lessons</h1>
<p>Emulating nature’s lessons involves taking the abstracted design strategy and applying it to our specific problem. In this case, we’re designing a VR interface that allows users to interact with virtual objects in a natural and intuitive way.</p>
<p>Here’s how we can emulate nature’s lessons:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>Direct Manipulation</strong>: We’ll allow users to interact directly with virtual objects using their hands or controllers. This will involve tracking the user’s hand movements and translating them into actions within the VR environment.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Multi-Sensory Feedback</strong>: We’ll provide feedback through multiple senses to help users understand the results of their actions. This could involve visual changes in the VR environment, sounds, and haptic feedback through the controllers.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Contextual Information</strong>: We’ll use visual and auditory cues to provide contextual information. For example, objects might get larger as they get closer, or make different sounds depending on their material.</p></li>
</ol>
<p>By emulating these features of human interaction with physical objects, we can create a VR interface that feels natural and intuitive to use.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/demo_to_game/virtual_interactions.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 04:55:59 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
