<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>V-Sekai - Manuals</title>
<link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/features.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/features.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 22:58:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/features/qa_process.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="v-sekai-qa-flow" class="level1">
<h1>V-Sekai QA Flow</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li>Ensure Play IK still functions properly.</li>
<li>Verify networking with three clients.</li>
<li>Check load times.</li>
</ol>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/features/qa_process.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 22:58:29 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/features/play_latest.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="play-the-latest-build" class="level1">
<h1>Play the latest build</h1>
<p>Instructions last checked 2023-08-13.</p>
<p>V-Sekai uses rolling releases and is alpha quality.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Alpha software may not contain all of the features that are planned for the final version. Alpha software is not thoroughly tested by the developer before it is released to customers. (Definition from Wikipedia.)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Our V-Sekai CI is located at <a href="https://ci.v-sekai.cloud">ci.v-sekai.cloud</a> - you must use Guest to login, since GitLab is admin-only.</p>
<p>Here are links to each of the latest jobs. Generally, you will want to click the Artifacts tab from each of these to download things.</p>
<section id="editor-linux-windows" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="editor-linux-windows">Editor (linux, windows):</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://ci.v-sekai.cloud/go/tab/build/detail/godot-groups-editor/latest/defaultStage/latest/linux_job">linux_job</a></li>
<li><a href="https://ci.v-sekai.cloud/go/tab/build/detail/godot-groups-editor/latest/defaultStage/latest/windows_job">windows_job</a></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="templates.tpz-for-making-export" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="templates.tpz-for-making-export">templates.tpz (for making export):</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://ci.v-sekai.cloud/go/tab/build/detail/godot-groups-editor/latest/templateZipStage/latest/defaultJob">default_job</a></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="v-sekai-demo-release-linux-windows" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="v-sekai-demo-release-linux-windows">V-Sekai demo release (linux, windows):</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://ci.v-sekai.cloud/go/files/groups-export/latest/exportStage/latest/linux_job/export_linuxbsd">linuxDesktopJob</a></li>
<li><a href="https://ci.v-sekai.cloud/go/tab/build/detail/groups-export/latest/exportStage/latest/windows_job">windowsJob</a></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="direct-.zip-downloads-of-the-releases-can-be-found-here-linux-windows" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="direct-.zip-downloads-of-the-releases-can-be-found-here-linux-windows">Direct .zip downloads of the releases can be found here (linux, windows):</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://ci.v-sekai.cloud/go/files/groups-export/latest/exportStage/latest/linux_job/export_linuxbsd.zip">export_linuxbsd.zip</a></li>
<li><a href="https://ci.v-sekai.cloud/go/files/groups-export/latest/exportStage/latest/windows_job/export_windows.zip">export_windows.zip</a></li>
</ul>
<p>The included .exe are fully functioning Godot editors. However, note that the .exe will not function properly as an editor unless you copy it or rename to be different from the .pck. Again, you must use Guest when it asks you to sign in then, from those links, you can click the Artifacts tab.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/features/play_latest.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 22:58:29 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/features/help_write_documentation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="help-us-write-about-v-sekai" class="level1">
<h1>Help Us Write About V-Sekai</h1>
<p>We aim to create comprehensive documentation for developers and users, covering all significant features and topics. Each feature requires a dedicated page with a descriptive title and a bullet list of essential points the user needs to learn.</p>
<section id="example-topic-godot-xr" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="example-topic-godot-xr">Example Topic: Godot XR</h2>
<p>For instance, when writing about Godot XR, the user should learn:</p>
<ul>
<li>What is XR (link to a page or provide a brief explanation)</li>
<li>What is Godot (link to a previous page if covered, and briefly re-explain in one sentence)</li>
<li>How XR works in Godot and how our product utilizes it</li>
<li>Concrete achievements possible with this feature/knowledge</li>
<li>Limitations of the technology affecting our product</li>
</ul>
<p>Draft each page as a bullet list like this, allowing writers to quickly understand the points to cover.</p>
</section>
<section id="step-by-step-instructions" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="step-by-step-instructions">Step-by-Step Instructions</h2>
<p>For cases where users need to follow steps, detail each step using straightforward language. Be consistent with verbs and phrasing to minimize cognitive load. For example:</p>
<section id="changing-game-resolution" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="changing-game-resolution">Changing Game Resolution</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Open the Project -&gt; Project Settings… menu.</li>
<li>Navigate to Display -&gt; Window in the left column. The game’s window settings appear on the right.</li>
<li>Scroll down to the resolution setting.</li>
<li>Click the numbers to change the resolution (values are in pixels).</li>
</ol>
<p>Consistently use verbs like:</p>
<ul>
<li>Click a button</li>
<li>Open a menu</li>
<li>Open a file</li>
<li>Navigate to a tab</li>
</ul>
<p>Keeping things simple, clear, and consistent makes it easier for users to concentrate on the process and remember new details.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="prompting-guides." class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="prompting-guides.">Prompting guides.</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>Use <code>be concise</code> to reduce costs.</li>
<li>I like <code>be concise, use plain style and use grade school language</code>. for the writing style.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="contributors" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="contributors">Contributors</h2>
<p>This page was written with advice from gdquest.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/features/help_write_documentation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 22:58:29 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/features/designing_games.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="designing-a-game" class="level1">
<h1>Designing a game</h1>
<section id="step-1-define-your-setting" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="step-1-define-your-setting">Step 1: Define Your Setting</h2>
<p>The setting is the environment where your game takes place. It’s what the player will see and interact with. The location could be a specific period (like 1950s post-apocalypse America), a genre (like high fantasy or low-tech sci-fi), or a combination of both. The setting should immediately excite the player and hint at a world of possibilities.</p>
<p>Here are some questions to help you define your setting:</p>
<ul>
<li>What does the world look like?</li>
<li>What kind of technology or magic exists?</li>
<li>What kinds of creatures or people live there?</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="step-2-create-your-story" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="step-2-create-your-story">Step 2: Create Your Story</h2>
<p>The story is what your players will experience as they play your game. It motivates the player to continue playing and helps them feel immersed in your game world.</p>
<p>Here are some questions to help you create your story:</p>
<ul>
<li>What is the central conflict or problem that needs to be solved?</li>
<li>Who are the main characters, and what are their goals?</li>
<li>What events will occur as the player progresses through the game?</li>
</ul>
<p>Remember, the setting is the backdrop for your story, but it’s not the same thing as the story itself.</p>
</section>
<section id="step-3-design-your-systems" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="step-3-design-your-systems">Step 3: Design Your Systems</h2>
<p>The systems, or mechanics, are how the player interacts with your game. They define what actions the player can take, what challenges they’ll face, and what strategies they can use to overcome those challenges.</p>
<p>Here are some questions to help you design your systems:</p>
<ul>
<li>What actions can the player take?</li>
<li>How does the player interact with the game world?</li>
<li>What challenges will the player face, and how can they overcome them?</li>
</ul>
<p>Once you’ve defined your setting, created your story, and designed your systems, you’ll have a game loop set in an exciting tale with player motivation. Remember to focus on one step at a time to avoid getting overwhelmed!</p>
</section>
<section id="reference" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="reference">Reference</h2>
<p>Discussion between Fire and Brune.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/features/designing_games.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 22:58:29 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/features/community_tools.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="community-tools" class="level1">
<h1>Community tools</h1>
<p>Obtain a dynamic date-time representation in your Discord messages: <a href="https://r.3v.fi/discord-timestamps/">https://r.3v.fi/discord-timestamps/</a></p>
<p>When2meet assists in determining the optimal time for a group gathering. This free, user-friendly survey tool streamlines the process. <a href="https://www.when2meet.com/">https://www.when2meet.com/</a></p>
<p>Self-hostable, Penpot is a design &amp; prototype platform that brings design freedom to your product team. Godot Engine can import svg exports from Penpot. <a href="https://penpot.app/">https://penpot.app/</a></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/features/community_tools.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 22:58:29 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/features/build_games.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="creating-virtual-reality-games-with-v-sekai" class="level1">
<h1>Creating Virtual Reality Games with V-Sekai</h1>
<section id="supported-file-types" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="supported-file-types">Supported File Types</h2>
<p>V-Sekai supports various file types out of the box, including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Audio: <code>.ogg</code>, <code>.mp3</code>, <code>.wav</code></li>
<li>Image: <code>.png</code>, <code>.jpg</code>, <code>.tga</code>, <code>.exr</code></li>
<li>Text, and more</li>
<li>Raw 3D Mesh: <code>.obj</code></li>
</ul>
<section id="gltf2-specification" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="gltf2-specification">glTF2 Specification</h3>
<p>We use the royalty-free 3D content specification, glTF2. It’s easy-to-read JSON format and is extensible with Khronos extension registry on Github. It replaces proprietary FBX and older COLLADA formats and has wide application support (Blender, Godot, etc.). It’s an ISO/IEC 12113 standard and adopted by Unity, Unreal Engine, and other software.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="virtual-reality-support" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="virtual-reality-support">Virtual Reality Support</h2>
<p>V-Sekai runs on OpenXR and Vulkan.</p>
</section>
<section id="godot-user-tools" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="godot-user-tools">Godot User Tools</h2>
<p>We provide a file loader for various file types (2D &amp; 3D assets, scenes, scripts, meshes, textures) and editable assets within the editor.</p>
</section>
<section id="scripting" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="scripting">Scripting</h2>
<p>We offer a built-in script editor, GDScript: In-house scripting language, GDExtension: C++ binding ABI with cross-version compatibility, and C++ Modules: Native performance.</p>
</section>
<section id="sandbox-scripting-environment-wip" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sandbox-scripting-environment-wip">Sandbox Scripting Environment (WIP)</h2>
<p>We’re actively researching a security-focused sandboxing environment. You can follow our progress on the <a href="https://github.com/ashtonmeuser/godot-wasm">godot-wasm project</a>.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/features/build_games.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 22:58:29 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/features/be_an_avatar_visit_places.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="v-sekai-your-avatar-your-world" class="level1">
<h1>V-Sekai: Your Avatar, Your World</h1>
<p>V-Sekai is a unique platform that allows you to import and explore various worlds. While we’re still working on our documentation, we welcome contributions and encourage users to reach out to us through our community channels for any questions or assistance.</p>
<section id="embrace-your-virtual-self-with-vrm-avatars-in-v-sekai" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="embrace-your-virtual-self-with-vrm-avatars-in-v-sekai">Embrace Your Virtual Self with VRM Avatars in V-Sekai</h2>
<p>One of the key features of V-Sekai is its support for VRM avatar files. VRM is an open-source standard designed to enable the sharing of portable humanoid avatars across different virtual reality platforms.</p>
<p>As a user, you can personalize your avatars in V-Sekai by importing models from Blender or VRoid Hub. These models then become your virtual persona within the space. For more information on VRM, please refer to <a href="https://www.khronos.org/assets/uploads/developers/presentations/VRM-Extending-glTF-for-Portable-Humanoid-Avatars_SIGGRAPH-Asia_Nov19.pdf">VRM: Extending glTF for Portable Humanoid Avatars</a>.</p>
<p>The VRM glTF2 extension plays a crucial role in V-Sekai, introducing a host of exciting features. It enables the creation of XR avatars built on glTF, providing an immersive experience for users. The extension also supports automatic humanoid rigging, making it easier to create and control character models.</p>
<p>Interactive hair and clothing add a touch of realism to the avatars, while twist bones and constraints provide more flexibility in movement and posing. Toon shading with glTF PBR gives the avatars a distinctive visual style, and face shapes for speech allow for more expressive communication within the virtual space.</p>
<p>Cross-engine support ensures that the VRM glTF2 extension can be used across different platforms, enhancing its versatility. The extension also simplifies physics simulation through spring bones, resulting in more natural and fluid movements. Meta-information such as author and license details can be included, and custom facial expressions or morphs can be created for a personalized touch.</p>
<p>Animation retargeting is another feature that enhances the user experience in V-Sekai. This feature allows you to import models or animation libraries, use the built-in humanoid profile, or even create custom profiles for unique characters like monsters or animals. It offers compatibility with Mixamo and Blender animations, allowing users to incorporate a wide range of movements into their avatars. Furthermore, walk and run animations can be blended using blend spaces, creating seamless transitions between different types of movement.</p>
</section>
<section id="journey-of-character-avatar-import-development" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="journey-of-character-avatar-import-development">Journey of Character Avatar Import Development</h2>
<p>Here’s a timeline that illustrates the development process of character avatar import:</p>
<pre class="mermaid"><code>gantt
    dateFormat  YYYY-MM-DD
    title       Character Avatar Import Development

    section Tasks
    Implement FBX for glTF in Godot Engine :a1, 2018-12-01, 2022-04-30
    Godot 4.0 development                      :a5, 2019-03-01, 2023-03-31
    Debug and fix glTF import in Godot Engine :a2, 2019-07-01, 2019-08-12
    Blender fixed glTF import in May 2020      :a3, 2020-05-01, 2020-05-31
    Implement Godot Engine glTF export        :a4, 2021-01-04, 2021-01-04
    Reduz removed REST transform influence from skeleton bones :a10, 2021-10-13, 2021-10-13
    Reduz removed animation 3D transform track, replaced by loc/rot/scale tracks :a11, 2021-10-13, 2021-10-13
    Reduz implemented animation compression   :a8, 2021-10-25, 2021-10-25
    iFire added Blender import                 :a7, 2021-11-11, 2021-11-11
    Reduz implemented Animation Libraries     :a6, 2022-04-11, 2022-04-11
    iFire shepherded Add AnimationTree Advanced Expressions :a9, 2022-05-19, 2022-05-19</code></pre>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://v-sekai.github.io/manuals/features/be_an_avatar_visit_places.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 22:58:29 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
